{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "He is named -- his father.",
      "options": ["to", "of", "with", "after"],
      "answer": "after"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "'Not bene' means -",
      "options": ["For example", "Not sure", "Next page", "Mark well"],
      "answer": "Mark well"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Imbecility' is -",
      "options": ["Foolishness", "Inactivity", "Impartiality", "Wisdom"],
      "answer": "Wisdom"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The practice of keeping one wife or husband is called -",
      "options": ["Monogamy", "Polygamy", "Polyandry", "Paramour"],
      "answer": "Monogamy"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "'Malice' এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Affection", "Love", "Animosity", "Kindness"],
      "answer": "Animosity"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "A handicapped person is one who -",
      "options": [
        "Works at handicraft",
        "Suffers from some disability",
        "Assigns handicaps to contestants",
        "Gives training in manual skill"
      ],
      "answer": "Suffers from some disability"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Find out the synonym of 'Remote'.",
      "options": ["Immediate", "Close", "Intimate", "Distant"],
      "answer": "Distant"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "'Handy' means -",
      "options": [
        "Comfortable",
        "Useful",
        "Necessary",
        "Convenient to handle or use"
      ],
      "answer": "Convenient to handle or use"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "She tried to be serious but she couldn't help ----- ?",
      "options": ["laughing", "to laugh", "laugh", "that to laugh"],
      "answer": "laughing"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Cease' ?",
      "options": ["Start", "Attractive", "Withdraw", "Sure"],
      "answer": "Start"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "\"Jamil was puny baby, but thanks to his mother's care, he grew into a --- lad.\" Fill in the blank with one of the following most nearly opposite in meaning of the sentence.",
      "options": ["sturdy", "fall", "great", "fat"],
      "answer": "sturdy"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Select the answer of the word 'Stagflation'",
      "options": [
        "Controlled prices",
        "Economic slow down",
        "Cultural dullness",
        "A disintegrating government"
      ],
      "answer": "Economic slow down"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "Choose the meaning of the given expression: 'A bird in hand is worth two in the bush'",
      "options": [
        "Take what you have got readily available rather than expecting better in the future",
        "The seen is better than the unseen",
        "Promises are better than actuals",
        "It is no good beating about the bush"
      ],
      "answer": "Take what you have got readily available rather than expecting better in the future"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "'Invidious' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Offensive", "Hateful", "Envious", "Charitable"],
      "answer": "Charitable"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "Overwork will tell --- your health.",
      "options": ["upon", "at", "a scape goat", "with"],
      "answer": "upon"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "He does not attend --- his office timely.",
      "options": ["to", "in", "at", "on"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "A Machiavellian character is ---",
      "options": [
        "An honest person",
        "A scheming person",
        "An adventurous person",
        "A learned person"
      ],
      "answer": "A scheming person"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "Opinion শব্দটির synonym হচ্ছে -",
      "options": ["Fact", "Knowledge", "Misgiving", "Belief"],
      "answer": "Belief"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "Choose the word opposite in meaning to the given word: 'Equity'",
      "options": ["Uprightness", "Justice", "Integrity", "Bias"],
      "answer": "Bias"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "'Prior to' means -",
      "options": ["after", "before", "immediately", "during the period of"],
      "answer": "before"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "Which one is a noun?",
      "options": ["Cute", "Acute", "Fluted", "Mute"],
      "answer": "Fluted"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "A drowning man catches ---- a straw.",
      "options": ["at", "with", "on", "of"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "I congratulate him ---- his success.",
      "options": ["on", "at", "in", "from"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "What is the meaning of 'doubtful' in -- 'Because of a long drought, farmers are doubtful about the prospect of a good yield.",
      "options": ["fearful", "pessimistic", "debating", "uncertain"],
      "answer": "uncertain"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "Complete the sentence with appropriate words: The Tajmahal as said --- built by Shshjahan.",
      "options": [
        "to have begun",
        "to had been",
        "to have been",
        "to have become"
      ],
      "answer": "to have been"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "Please come ---- my office.",
      "options": ["by", "at", "on", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "Something that is 'fresh' is something ---",
      "options": [
        "Disrespectful",
        "In fairly good condition",
        "Pleasant",
        "Recently printed or published"
      ],
      "answer": "In fairly good condition"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "I decided to go --- with my friend as I needed some exercise.",
      "options": ["to a walk", "for a walk", "for walking", "walk"],
      "answer": "for a walk"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "Coalesce -এর-সমার্থক-শব্দ-কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Separate", "Unify", "Order", "Counterfeit"],
      "answer": "Unify"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "The car sped up as it went down the ramp. (Antonym)",
      "options": [
        "ascended",
        "descended",
        "exploded",
        "decelerated",
        "tumbled"
      ],
      "answer": "decelerated"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "question": "King শব্দটির Abstract form হবে ?",
      "options": ["Kingship", "King", "Kinghood", "উপরের কোনটিই নয়"],
      "answer": "Kingship"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "question": "I wish I --- my homework last night.",
      "options": ["did", "had done", "was doing", "am doing", "have done"],
      "answer": "had done"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "question": "He talks as if he --- everything.",
      "options": ["has known", "had known", "will know", "knew"],
      "answer": "knew"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "question": "A synonym for 'hindrance' is -",
      "options": ["solution", "barrier", "answer", "criticize", "opportunity"],
      "answer": "barrier"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'Dye'?",
      "options": ["Die", "Color", "Dig", "Divide"],
      "answer": "Color"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "question": "নিচের কোনটি Abstract Noun?",
      "options": ["Child", "Boy", "Family", "Childhood"],
      "answer": "Childhood"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "question": "The more she learnt ---- the American civil war, the more fascinated with it she became.",
      "options": ["of", "about", "in", "into"],
      "answer": ["of", "about"]
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "question": "'Hire a man' means -",
      "options": [
        "To bring a man",
        "To lend a man",
        "To employ a man",
        "To call a man"
      ],
      "answer": "To employ a man"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "question": "The word 'senile' is related to -",
      "options": ["Old age", "Senses", "Superiority", "Seniority"],
      "answer": "Old age"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Obesity' is -",
      "options": ["Very fat", "Tall", "Short", "Thin"],
      "answer": "Thin"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "question": "He was embroiled in litigations with his neighbours. The 'embroiled' word means -",
      "options": ["Enmeshed", "Employed", "Occupied", "Embittered"],
      "answer": "Enmeshed"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "question": "He is accessible --- all বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["of", "on", "into", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "question": "He was smiling --- himself and did not answer my question.",
      "options": ["with", "at", "after", "to"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "question": "I concur --- you on your decision. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["to", "with", "by", "upon"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Malignant' ?",
      "options": ["Harmful", "Vindictive", "Benign", "Morose"],
      "answer": "Benign"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "question": "What is the meaning of 'hang about'?",
      "options": ["Lag behind", "Keep about", "Loiter about", "Remain away"],
      "answer": "Loiter about"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "question": "Choose the right preposition for the following sentence: I hope you are not angry -- her.",
      "options": ["upon", "about", "with", "for"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "question": "I have no objection to ---- your story again.",
      "options": ["hear", "have hear", "hearing", "be heard"],
      "answer": "hearing"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "question": "A person working in the same place with another -",
      "options": ["Comrade", "Colleague", "Assistant", "Contemporary"],
      "answer": "Colleague"
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "question": "\"It is time to review the 'protocol' on testing nuclear weapons\". Here the 'protocol' word means---",
      "options": ["Record of rules", "Summary", "Procedures", "Problems"],
      "answer": "Record of rules"
    },
    {
      "id": 51,
      "question": "\"Familiarity breeds contempt\" বাক্যটির সঠিক বাংলা অনুবাদঃ",
      "options": [
        "বেশি কথা বলা অপমানকর",
        "পরিচয়ে শত্রুতা বাড়ে",
        "অতি মাখামাখি করলে মান থাকে না",
        "মানীকে গম্ভীর হতে হয়"
      ],
      "answer": "পরিচয়ে শত্রুতা বাড়ে"
    },
    {
      "id": 52,
      "question": "Meaning of 'Conjecture' is related to -",
      "options": ["Continuity", "Conjunction", "Guidance", "Guess"],
      "answer": "Guess"
    },
    {
      "id": 53,
      "question": "The word 'Plurality' means ---?",
      "options": [
        "The letter 'S'",
        "Men and women",
        "Chaos and confusion",
        "The holding of more than one office at a time"
      ],
      "answer": "The holding of more than one office at a time"
    },
    {
      "id": 54,
      "question": "Choose the correct synonym for 'Menacing' -",
      "options": ["Encouraging", "Alarming", "Promising", "Auspicious"],
      "answer": "Alarming"
    },
    {
      "id": 55,
      "question": "Select the word/words that express the opposite meaning to the underlined word/words.  The claim was found to be fraudulent.",
      "options": [
        "circumstantial",
        "ceremonial",
        "supportive",
        "genuine",
        "sneaky"
      ],
      "answer": "genuine"
    },
    {
      "id": 56,
      "question": "'Brief' শব্দটির synonym হচ্ছে ----",
      "options": ["Mental", "Momentary", "Endless", "Lasting"],
      "answer": "Momentary"
    },
    {
      "id": 57,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Pessimism' ?",
      "options": ["Positivism", "Optimism", "Primitivism", "Aestheticism"],
      "answer": "Optimism"
    },
    {
      "id": 58,
      "question": "'Achilles heel' means -",
      "options": [
        "A heel of Achilles",
        "The fault of Achilles",
        "Minor fault",
        "The fault which is small but can cause a person's fall"
      ],
      "answer": "The fault which is small but can cause a person's fall"
    },
    {
      "id": 59,
      "question": "'Fictitious' means",
      "options": ["Full of facts", "Factual", "Artificial", "True"],
      "answer": "Artificial"
    },
    {
      "id": 60,
      "question": "What is the antonym of \"Expel\" ?",
      "options": ["Banish", "Dismiss", "Eject", "Admit"],
      "answer": "Admit"
    },
    {
      "id": 71,
      "question": "A 'congenial' work environment enables a worker to perform better (find out synonym).",
      "options": ["Meticulous", "Friendly", "Solitary", "Easy", "Challenging"],
      "answer": "Friendly"
    },
    {
      "id": 72,
      "question": "I am convinced --- the necessity of prudence. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["with", "on", "in", "of"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 73,
      "question": "I have been suffering --- fever for the last two days.",
      "options": ["with", "from", "in", "of"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 74,
      "question": "These days everybody complains --- pollution.",
      "options": ["for", "against", "about", "of"],
      "answer": "about"
    },
    {
      "id": 75,
      "question": "Which sentence is correct ?",
      "options": [
        "A new cabinet has been sworn thin Dhaka",
        "A new cabinet has been sworn in Dhaka",
        "A new cabinet has been sworn by in Dhaka",
        "A new cabinet has sworn in Dhaka"
      ],
      "answer": "A new cabinet has been sworn in Dhaka"
    },
    {
      "id": 76,
      "question": "The word 'Lunar' is related to -",
      "options": ["Sun", "Light", "Moon", "Earth"],
      "answer": "Moon"
    },
    {
      "id": 77,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym of the word 'Sung'",
      "options": ["Tight", "New", "Loosed", "Asleep"],
      "answer": "Asleep"
    },
    {
      "id": 78,
      "question": "Which of the following four alternatives is not a tree?",
      "options": ["Pagoda", "Cedar", "Banyan", "Birch"],
      "answer": "Pagoda"
    },
    {
      "id": 79,
      "question": "Select the word closest in meaning to the word- রহস্যময়",
      "options": ["Efficient", "Mysterious", "Tiring", "Magical"],
      "answer": "Mysterious"
    },
    {
      "id": 80,
      "question": "Choose the correct preposition. He didn't ask me ----- ; he kept me standing at the door.",
      "options": ["for", "out", "after", "in"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 81,
      "question": "His sympathy ---- the poor is praise worthy.",
      "options": ["for", "with", "towards", "to"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 82,
      "question": "Nipa as well as her brothers (come) to me.",
      "options": ["have come", "are coming", "was came", "has come"],
      "answer": "has come"
    },
    {
      "id": 83,
      "question": "The word 'Odd' means",
      "options": ["Universal", "Huge", "Average", "Strange"],
      "answer": "Strange"
    },
    {
      "id": 84,
      "question": "The word ‘omnivorous’ means:",
      "options": [
        "eating all types of food",
        "eating only fruits",
        "eating only meat",
        "eating grass and plants only"
      ],
      "answer": "eating all types of food"
    },
    {
      "id": 85,
      "question": "'Frugal' means -",
      "options": ["waste", "wild", "economical", "hasty", "none of them"],
      "answer": "economical"
    },
    {
      "id": 86,
      "question": "Choose the correct sentence.",
      "options": [
        "I wish I was you",
        "I wish I were you",
        "I wish I am you",
        "I wish I are you"
      ],
      "answer": "I wish I were you"
    },
    {
      "id": 87,
      "question": "Ideal businessman is he who ---",
      "options": [
        "Looks to his own interests",
        "Look employer and worker interests",
        "Looks community interests",
        "Integrates interests of the groups above"
      ],
      "answer": "Integrates interests of the groups above"
    },
    {
      "id": 88,
      "question": "Do not make a noise while your father -----",
      "options": ["Is sleeping", "Has slept", "Asleep", "Is being asleep"],
      "answer": "Is sleeping"
    },
    {
      "id": 89,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Franchise'",
      "options": ["Privilege", "Utility", "French", "Frankness"],
      "answer": "Privilege"
    },
    {
      "id": 90,
      "question": "If you concede an idea you -",
      "options": [
        "Contradict it",
        "Brag about it",
        "Think it over carefully",
        "Insist on its importance",
        "Acknowledge it as true"
      ],
      "answer": "Acknowledge it as true"
    },
    {
      "id": 91,
      "question": "It is in human not only to kill but also to purchase the 'migratory' birds.",
      "options": ["Beautiful", "Native", "Temporary", "Bad", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Temporary"
    },
    {
      "id": 92,
      "question": "'Blockbuster' means ---?",
      "options": [
        "A large solid piece of stone",
        "A device to cut off a person's head as a punishment",
        "Something that makes movement difficult",
        "A powerful explosive to demolish buildings"
      ],
      "answer": "A powerful explosive to demolish buildings"
    },
    {
      "id": 93,
      "question": "The synonym for 'Abortive' -",
      "options": ["Fruitful", "Familiar", "Unsuccessful", "Consuming"],
      "answer": "Unsuccessful"
    },
    {
      "id": 94,
      "question": "Meteorology is the study of -",
      "options": [
        "Birds and animals",
        "The earth's atmosphere and its changes",
        "The universe",
        "Human behavior"
      ],
      "answer": "The earth's atmosphere and its changes"
    },
    {
      "id": 95,
      "question": "--- amazing song haunted me for a long time.",
      "options": ["These", "Those", "Thus", "That"],
      "answer": "That"
    },
    {
      "id": 96,
      "question": "The boys played football --- the rain.",
      "options": ["Under", "Amidst", "In", "During"],
      "answer": "During"
    },
    {
      "id": 97,
      "question": "I am fed up ----- waiting for her to telephone.",
      "options": ["With", "In", "By", "For"],
      "answer": "With"
    },
    {
      "id": 98,
      "question": "Focus is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "Disappear",
        "Acquired",
        "Redundant",
        "Sterile",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "None of these"
    },
    {
      "id": 99,
      "question": "Dhaka is a big city. এখানে City শব্দটি কোন প্রকারের Noun.",
      "options": ["Proper", "Common", "Collective", "Material"],
      "answer": "Common"
    },
    {
      "id": 100,
      "question": "Which of the following word is the correct synonym of 'Scurrilous' ?",
      "options": ["Compartmentalize", "Derogatory", "Clippers", "Bitty"],
      "answer": "Derogatory"
    },
    {
      "id": 101,
      "question": "Select the alternative which best expresses the meaning of the given sentences: 'We were no more surprised than Rahman'",
      "options": [
        "We were less surprised than Rahman",
        "We were all surprised",
        "Rahman was less surprised than us",
        "We were as surprised as Rahman"
      ],
      "answer": "We were as surprised as Rahman"
    },
    {
      "id": 102,
      "question": "The appropriate meaning of the word 'Polygamy' is --",
      "options": [
        "The crime of marrying somebody when you are still married to somebody",
        "The custom of being married to only one person at a particular time",
        "Custom of having more than one husband at the same time",
        "Custom of having more than one wife at the same time"
      ],
      "answer": "Custom of having more than one wife at the same time"
    },
    {
      "id": 103,
      "question": "If a substance is cohesive, it tends of -",
      "options": [
        "Retain heat",
        "Bend without too much difficulties",
        "Stick together",
        "Break easily"
      ],
      "answer": "Stick together"
    },
    {
      "id": 104,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Tremor' is -",
      "options": ["Struggle", "Revolt", "Shake", "Departure"],
      "answer": "Shake"
    },
    {
      "id": 105,
      "question": "Vague is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "Expressive",
        "Felicitous",
        "Well-defined",
        "Provocation",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Well-defined"
    },
    {
      "id": 106,
      "question": "Fill in the gap with proper word: This pen is inferior ---- your pen.",
      "options": ["Than", "That", "From", "To"],
      "answer": "To"
    },
    {
      "id": 107,
      "question": "The girl prides herself ---- her beauty.",
      "options": ["In", "For", "Of", "On"],
      "answer": "On"
    },
    {
      "id": 108,
      "question": "When one is 'Pragmatic' he is being……..",
      "options": ["Wasteful", "Productive", "Practical", "Fussy"],
      "answer": "Practical"
    },
    {
      "id": 109,
      "question": "When your plane ----, please call me. Complete the sentence by using the appropriate word",
      "options": ["Will arrive", "Arrives", "Arrived", "Will have arrived"],
      "answer": "Arrives"
    },
    {
      "id": 110,
      "question": "Few people would care to take the negative side of the preposition that the women of the world are --- & ---",
      "options": ["At", "With", "Of", "In"],
      "answer": "With"
    },
    {
      "id": 171,
      "question": "'Mitigated' is most nearly opposite to -",
      "options": ["Repecated", "Raised", "Terminated", "Aggravated", "Risen"],
      "answer": "Aggravated"
    },
    {
      "id": 172,
      "question": "Synonyms of Charlatan",
      "options": ["Bilingual", "Deserter", "Imposter", "Revamp"],
      "answer": "Imposter"
    },
    {
      "id": 173,
      "question": "His friends mourned ---- the death ---- his mother.",
      "options": ["On , over", "At , of", "Over , of", "Of , of"],
      "answer": "At , of"
    },
    {
      "id": 174,
      "question": "'You look terrific in that dress!' The word 'terrific' in the above sentence means –",
      "options": ["Excellent", "Funny", "Very ugly", "Horrible"],
      "answer": "Excellent"
    },
    {
      "id": 175,
      "question": "Frustration results --- violence.",
      "options": ["At", "In", "Of", "With"],
      "answer": "In"
    },
    {
      "id": 176,
      "question": "Proclaim' means:",
      "options": ["Pronounce", "Declare", "Announce", "Circulate"],
      "answer": "Announce"
    },
    {
      "id": 177,
      "question": "Select the antonym of 'Bless' ?",
      "options": ["Blame", "Abuse", "Sool", "Curse"],
      "answer": "Curse"
    },
    {
      "id": 178,
      "question": "The antonym of the word 'Somber' is",
      "options": ["Bright", "Gloomy", "Dismal", "Dark"],
      "answer": "Bright"
    },
    {
      "id": 179,
      "question": "There is a bridge ---- the river.",
      "options": ["On", "Over", "Ford", "Above"],
      "answer": "Over"
    },
    {
      "id": 180,
      "question": "The word ‘sibling’ means-",
      "options": ["A brother", "A sister", "A brother or sister", "An infant"],
      "answer": "A brother or sister"
    },
    {
      "id": 181,
      "question": "The Headmaster is ---- the School .",
      "options": ["In", "On", "Of", "With"],
      "answer": "In"
    },
    {
      "id": 182,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Termination' is -",
      "options": ["End", "Rare", "Cultivation", "Activation", "Modification"],
      "answer": "End"
    },
    {
      "id": 183,
      "question": "Walt Whitman was the great Emancipator of the form and spirit of American poetry.",
      "options": ["Master", "Liberator", "Enthusiast", "Designer", "Follower"],
      "answer": "Liberator"
    },
    {
      "id": 184,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Inception' is -",
      "options": ["Insertion", "Progression", "Starting", "Innovation"],
      "answer": "Starting"
    },
    {
      "id": 185,
      "question": "Give the synonym of 'Bombastic' -",
      "options": ["Sensitive", "Pompous", "Rapid", "Sufficient"],
      "answer": "Pompous"
    },
    {
      "id": 186,
      "question": "Wordsworth introduced the readers --- a new kind of poetry.",
      "options": ["With", "At", "To", "By"],
      "answer": "To"
    },
    {
      "id": 187,
      "question": "'Exonerate' means -",
      "options": ["Absolve", "Praise", "Condemn", "Defer"],
      "answer": "Absolve"
    },
    {
      "id": 188,
      "question": "One should cling ---- one's plan.",
      "options": ["With", "To", "Of", "For"],
      "answer": "To"
    },
    {
      "id": 189,
      "question": "The man was charged --- theft.",
      "options": ["At", "In", "Of", "With"],
      "answer": "With"
    },
    {
      "id": 190,
      "question": "'Amplitude' শব্দের বাংলা পরিভাষা নিম্নের কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["বিস্তৃত", "বিস্তার", "প্রসারিত"],
      "answer": "বিস্তার"
    },
    {
      "id": 191,
      "question": "English (to speak) in many parts of the world.",
      "options": [
        "English is spoken in many parts of the world.",
        "The English is spoken in many parts of the world.",
        "English is being spoken in many parts of the world."
      ],
      "answer": "English is spoken in many parts of the world."
    },
    {
      "id": 192,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'Belated'?",
      "options": ["Complaining", "Off hand", "Weak", "Tardy"],
      "answer": "Tardy"
    },
    {
      "id": 193,
      "question": "The man was accused --- murder.",
      "options": ["To", "Of", "With", "For"],
      "answer": "Of"
    },
    {
      "id": 194,
      "question": "First language means the --- language.",
      "options": ["Important", "Main", "Natural", "Official"],
      "answer": "Natural"
    },
    {
      "id": 195,
      "question": "I wish today ----- Friday.",
      "options": ["Is", "Was", "Were", "Will be"],
      "answer": "Were"
    },
    {
      "id": 196,
      "question": "'Large' এর বিপরীত শব্দ -------?",
      "options": ["Big", "Small", "Wasted", "Capacious"],
      "answer": "Small"
    },
    {
      "id": 197,
      "question": "Our school is ---- the main road.",
      "options": ["On", "In", "To", "By"],
      "answer": "On"
    },
    {
      "id": 198,
      "question": "A person who sells fruits and vegetables -",
      "options": [
        "A vegetable man",
        "A vegetarian",
        "A green grocer",
        "A hawker"
      ],
      "answer": "A green grocer"
    },
    {
      "id": 199,
      "question": "Choose the correct synonym for 'Buccaneer' ?",
      "options": ["Bachelor", "Presenter", "Pirated", "Butcher"],
      "answer": "Pirated"
    },
    {
      "id": 200,
      "question": "'Conduit' is nearest meaning to -",
      "options": [
        "Water tape",
        "Pipe",
        "Electricity cable",
        "Moisture on windows panes"
      ],
      "answer": "Pipe"
    },
    {
      "id": 201,
      "question": "He is proud --- his position.",
      "options": ["Of", "For", "At", "In"],
      "answer": "Of"
    },
    {
      "id": 202,
      "question": "A person who enters without any invitation",
      "options": ["Burglar", "Intruder", "Thief", "Vandal"],
      "answer": "Intruder"
    },
    {
      "id": 203,
      "question": "Time after twilight and before night --- ?",
      "options": ["Evening", "Dawn", "Dusk", "Eclipse"],
      "answer": "Dusk"
    },
    {
      "id": 204,
      "question": "He is innocent ---- the charge.",
      "options": ["With", "To", "Of", "At"],
      "answer": "Of"
    },
    {
      "id": 205,
      "question": "What word is the right antonym for 'initiative'?",
      "options": ["Apathy", "Indolence", "Enterprise", "Activity"],
      "answer": "Indolence"
    },
    {
      "id": 206,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Restricted' is -",
      "options": ["Confidential", "Accessible", "Communique", "Report"],
      "answer": "Confidential"
    },
    {
      "id": 207,
      "question": "What is the most appropriate word for the blank in the following sentence: 'One who creates fear as a weapon for power is a ---",
      "options": ["Terrorist", "Militant", "Extremist", "Anarchist"],
      "answer": "Anarchist"
    },
    {
      "id": 208,
      "question": "Mistakes should be pointed ---- in a student's work.",
      "options": ["Up", "Upon", "Out", "On"],
      "answer": "Out"
    },
    {
      "id": 209,
      "question": "Something which is obnoxious means that it is----",
      "options": [
        "Very dangerous",
        "Very pleasant",
        "Very ugly",
        "Very unpleasant"
      ],
      "answer": "Very unpleasant"
    },
    {
      "id": 210,
      "question": "He has paid the penalty --- his crimes --- five years in prison.",
      "options": ["For , with", "At , by", "About , at", "Of , of"],
      "answer": "For , with"
    },
    {
      "id": 211,
      "question": "Complete the sentence : As the sun ---, I decided to go out.",
      "options": ["Shines", "Has shone", "Shined", "Was shining"],
      "answer": "Was shining"
    },
    {
      "id": 212,
      "question": "What would be the best antonym of 'hibernate'?",
      "options": ["Dormancy", "Sluggishness", "Liveliness", "Democracy"],
      "answer": "Liveliness"
    },
    {
      "id": 213,
      "question": "The word 'Nuptial' is related to -",
      "options": ["Marriage", "Night", "Sleep", "Love"],
      "answer": "Marriage"
    },
    {
      "id": 214,
      "question": "Ended in Fascio means -",
      "options": [
        "Complete failure",
        "On the verge of failure",
        "Yet to be failure",
        "None of them"
      ],
      "answer": "Complete failure"
    },
    {
      "id": 215,
      "question": "I have great respect ---- him.",
      "options": ["Of", "In", "For", "To"],
      "answer": "For"
    },
    {
      "id": 216,
      "question": "The meaning of the word 'Euphemism'?",
      "options": [
        "Vague idea",
        "In offensive expression",
        "A sonnet",
        "Wise saying"
      ],
      "answer": "In offensive expression"
    },
    {
      "id": 217,
      "question": "He is learning --- the wall .",
      "options": ["With", "Upon", "To", "Against"],
      "answer": "Against"
    },
    {
      "id": 218,
      "question": "Meaning of the word 'Shun' is -",
      "options": ["Pursue", "Pure", "Actual", "Avoid"],
      "answer": "Avoid"
    },
    {
      "id": 219,
      "question": "Synonym of 'emancipate' -",
      "options": ["Set free", "Take back", "Make worse", "Embolden"],
      "answer": "Set free"
    },
    {
      "id": 220,
      "question": "But for your timely help , I would failed and I am forever indebted to you .",
      "options": ["Of", "Have", "Without", "Since"],
      "answer": "Have"
    },
    {
      "id": 221,
      "question": "A synonym for 'Hostility' -",
      "options": ["Enmity", "Cruelty", "Hospitality", "Friendship"],
      "answer": "Enmity"
    },
    {
      "id": 222,
      "question": "Which word is not synonymous of 'Belief' ?",
      "options": ["Credence", "Incredible", "Faith", "Conviction"],
      "answer": "Incredible"
    },
    {
      "id": 223,
      "question": "'Rule of thumb' means--",
      "options": [
        "a rule based on science",
        "a bad rule",
        "a rule that must be obeyed",
        "a rule based on past experience rather than on theory"
      ],
      "answer": "a rule based on past experience rather than on theory"
    },
    {
      "id": 224,
      "question": "The man is involved ---- the affair. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে --",
      "options": ["on", "with", "in", "to"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 225,
      "question": "One who possesses many talents -",
      "options": ["Versatile", "Gifted", "Exceptional", "Nubile"],
      "answer": "Versatile"
    },
    {
      "id": 226,
      "question": "'Anonymous' -এর সঠিক বাংলা নিচের কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["অনামা", "অজ্ঞাত", "এলোমেলো"],
      "answer": "অনামা"
    },
    {
      "id": 227,
      "question": "Are you doing anything special --- the weekend ?",
      "options": ["in", "for", "on", "at"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 228,
      "question": "I took a map with me, as I didn't want to ---- my way on the journey.",
      "options": [
        "loose (ঢিলা)",
        "lose (হারানো)",
        "lost (হারিয়েছিল)",
        "loss (ক্ষতি)"
      ],
      "answer": "lose (হারানো)"
    },
    {
      "id": 229,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'Economical' ?",
      "options": ["Meager", "Miser", "Frugal", "Expensive"],
      "answer": "Frugal"
    },
    {
      "id": 230,
      "question": "There is no alternative ---- training.",
      "options": ["to", "for", "than", "of"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 231,
      "question": "The antonym of the word 'Eternal' is",
      "options": ["Permanent", "Essential", "Temporary", "Unnecessary"],
      "answer": "Temporary"
    },
    {
      "id": 232,
      "question": "Immense এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Small", "Proud", "Enormous", "Boastful"],
      "answer": "Enormous"
    },
    {
      "id": 233,
      "question": "Bangladesh was liberated --- 1971.",
      "options": ["on", "at", "before", "in"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 234,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a meaning of the word \"Rural\" ?",
      "options": ["Country", "Rustic", "Pastoral", "Bucolic", "Botany"],
      "answer": "Botany"
    },
    {
      "id": 235,
      "question": "Which one is the antonym 'Pacific' ?",
      "options": ["Calm", "Courageous", "Zealous", "Agitated"],
      "answer": "Agitated"
    },
    {
      "id": 236,
      "question": "One who eats everything is called -",
      "options": ["Omniscient", "Omnipotent", "Omnivorous", "Omnipresent"],
      "answer": "Omnivorous"
    },
    {
      "id": 237,
      "question": "Indigenous is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "thoughtful",
        "dispersed",
        "link",
        "activate",
        "none of them"
      ],
      "answer": "none of them"
    },
    {
      "id": 238,
      "question": "I always confide --- you. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["in", "at", "on", "with"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 239,
      "question": "Camouflage' means:",
      "options": ["disguise", "difficult", "heavy", "dangerous"],
      "answer": "disguise"
    },
    {
      "id": 240,
      "question": "'Gain' এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Promote", "Advantage", "Fulfill", "Trouble"],
      "answer": "Advantage"
    },
    {
      "id": 241,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym for the word 'Obese'?",
      "options": ["Fat", "Slim", "Thick", "Goal"],
      "answer": "Slim"
    },
    {
      "id": 242,
      "question": "EXCESS is most nearly similar in meaning to -",
      "options": ["Durable", "Exploit", "Continuous", "Surplus"],
      "answer": "Surplus"
    },
    {
      "id": 243,
      "question": "'Deformed' শব্দের synonym হচ্ছে -",
      "options": ["Crippled", "Beautiful", "Determined", "Handsome"],
      "answer": "Crippled"
    },
    {
      "id": 244,
      "question": "Antonym of 'Wax\" is -",
      "options": ["Peace", "Wane", "Cruel", "Agree"],
      "answer": "Wane"
    },
    {
      "id": 245,
      "question": "The Queen is said --- Australia next year .",
      "options": [
        "to have visited",
        "to visit",
        "to be visiting",
        "that she will visit"
      ],
      "answer": "to be visiting"
    },
    {
      "id": 246,
      "question": "He won a victory --- his rivals.",
      "options": ["over", "against", "from", "off"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 247,
      "question": "বাংলায় \"ছড়া\" শব্দের ইংরেজী ---",
      "options": ["Poem", "Poetry", "Lyric", "Rhyme"],
      "answer": "Rhyme"
    },
    {
      "id": 248,
      "question": "'I help you '. Here help implies -",
      "options": ["Promise", "Threat", "Command", "Simple futurity"],
      "answer": "Promise"
    },
    {
      "id": 249,
      "question": "The 'anthropology' is related to --",
      "options": [
        "Music",
        "Philosophy",
        "The study of mathematics",
        "The study of mankind"
      ],
      "answer": "The study of mankind"
    },
    {
      "id": 250,
      "question": "The English took them for Egyptians means -",
      "options": [
        "The English considered them to be Egyptians",
        "The English took them to the Egyptians",
        "The English were taken in by the Egyptians",
        "The English brought them as far as to Egypt"
      ],
      "answer": "The English considered them to be Egyptians"
    },
    {
      "id": 251,
      "question": "Choose the alternatives that best replace the underlined words in the following sentences.  In Bangladesh, gender discrimination deters population control and poverty alleviation.",
      "options": ["justify", "impede", "progress", "help", "stimulate"],
      "answer": "impede"
    },
    {
      "id": 252,
      "question": "I don't think you will have any difficulty --- a driving license.",
      "options": ["to get", "in getting", "for getting", "get"],
      "answer": "in getting"
    },
    {
      "id": 253,
      "question": "Choose the answer that is closest in meaning to the following sentence:\"Despite the great difference in size,shape and function,all human cells have the same 46 chromosomes\".",
      "options": [
        "All human cells are the same because the 46 chromosomes govern size, shape and function",
        "Difference in size, shape and function are not very great because all human cells have the same 46 chromosomes",
        "The size, shape and function of human cells are the same, but 46 chromosomes are different",
        "Although the 46 chromosomes are the same in all human cells, there are differences in the size, shape and function"
      ],
      "answer": "Although the 46 chromosomes are the same in all human cells, there are differences in the size, shape and function"
    },
    {
      "id": 254,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Organize' is -",
      "options": ["gathering", "scattering", "dispersing", "disorganize"],
      "answer": "disorganize"
    },
    {
      "id": 255,
      "question": "Now a days many villages are lit ---- Electricity.",
      "options": ["with", "by", "from", "on"],
      "answer": "by"
    },
    {
      "id": 256,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym for the word 'Inane' -",
      "options": ["Mellow", "Wise", "Intoxicated", "Silent"],
      "answer": "Wise"
    },
    {
      "id": 257,
      "question": "The word 'Rendezvous' means",
      "options": [
        "An appointed meeting place for troops",
        "An appointed meeting place for teachers",
        "An appointed meeting place for political leaders",
        "An appointed meeting place for students"
      ],
      "answer": "An appointed meeting place for troops"
    },
    {
      "id": 258,
      "question": "'Superstitious' means",
      "options": ["যাদুবিদ্যা", "কুসংস্কারচ্ছন্ন", "সেতুবন্ধন", "উপাসনা"],
      "answer": "কুসংস্কারচ্ছন্ন"
    },
    {
      "id": 259,
      "question": "Had I been a millionare I (establish) a hospital.",
      "options": [
        "established",
        "would have established",
        "would established",
        "would have been established"
      ],
      "answer": "would have established"
    },
    {
      "id": 260,
      "question": "Manifesto' means",
      "options": ["Punishment", "Comment", "Judgement", "Remark"],
      "answer": "Judgement"
    },
    {
      "id": 261,
      "question": "She has great fondness ---- classical music.",
      "options": ["of", "for", "in", "with"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 262,
      "question": "We should not depend ---- others.",
      "options": ["by", "in", "on", "with"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 263,
      "question": "''Raj wasn't the paragon of virtue Rashida had expected'' means -",
      "options": [
        "Rashida was disappointed in Raj",
        "Rashida was happy with Raj",
        "Rashida was not disappointed in Raj",
        "Rashida approved of Raj"
      ],
      "answer": "Rashida was disappointed in Raj"
    },
    {
      "id": 264,
      "question": "He was debarred form --- the the examination.",
      "options": ["taking", "sitting", "appearing", "regard"],
      "answer": "appearing"
    },
    {
      "id": 265,
      "question": "What is the general term for psychological treatment",
      "options": [
        "Psycholog",
        "Psychopathyc",
        "Psychotherapy",
        "Psychoanalysis"
      ],
      "answer": "Psychotherapy"
    },
    {
      "id": 266,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Insane' is -",
      "options": ["Stupid", "Crazy", "Senseless", "Indolent"],
      "answer": "Crazy"
    },
    {
      "id": 267,
      "question": "'Cataclysm' means",
      "options": [
        "Disorder",
        "Anarchy",
        "Violence",
        "Sudden violent change or disaster"
      ],
      "answer": "Sudden violent change or disaster"
    },
    {
      "id": 268,
      "question": "You are not amenable -- reason বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["from", "to", "of", "into"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 269,
      "question": "One versed in horsemanship is called -",
      "options": ["Horseman", "Rider", "Jockey", "Lancer"],
      "answer": "Jockey"
    },
    {
      "id": 270,
      "question": "Every driver must be held --- his own actions.",
      "options": [
        "responsible for",
        "responsible to",
        "liable to",
        "blamed for"
      ],
      "answer": "responsible for"
    },
    {
      "id": 271,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'Effigy' ?",
      "options": ["Proxy", "Profundity", "Boldness", "Dummy"],
      "answer": "Dummy"
    },
    {
      "id": 272,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'Delude' ?",
      "options": ["Demand", "Permit", "Aggravate", "Deceive"],
      "answer": "Deceive"
    },
    {
      "id": 273,
      "question": "He is blind --- his son's faults.",
      "options": ["of", "to", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 274,
      "question": "Antonym of the word 'Meticulous' is -",
      "options": ["Careless", "Meritorious", "Ordinary", "Careful"],
      "answer": "Careless"
    },
    {
      "id": 275,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Satisfaction' is -",
      "options": [
        "Triumph",
        "Achievement",
        "Conquer",
        "Contentment",
        "Pleasure"
      ],
      "answer": "Contentment"
    },
    {
      "id": 276,
      "question": "'Ruminant' means",
      "options": ["Cud-chewing animal", "Soup", "Gossip", "Noise maker"],
      "answer": "Cud-chewing animal"
    },
    {
      "id": 277,
      "question": "'Civil Society'- এর পরিভাষা নিচের কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["সভ্য সমাজ", "সুশীল সমাজ", "বেসামরিক সমাজ", "কোনটিই নয়"],
      "answer": "সুশীল সমাজ"
    },
    {
      "id": 278,
      "question": "When John looked at the list he saw that his name had been 'ommited'",
      "options": ["Passed out", "Put out", "Rubbed out", "Left out"],
      "answer": "Left out"
    },
    {
      "id": 279,
      "question": "The boy takes --- his grandfather.",
      "options": ["to", "with", "up", "after"],
      "answer": "after"
    },
    {
      "id": 280,
      "question": "Let us begin by looking at the (minutes) of the meeting. Here the bracket close word means -",
      "options": [
        "time record",
        "time frame",
        "written record",
        "written analysis"
      ],
      "answer": "written record"
    },
    {
      "id": 281,
      "question": "The antonym of \"Repulse\" is -",
      "options": ["Reside", "Emphasize", "Attract", "Impulse"],
      "answer": "Attract"
    },
    {
      "id": 282,
      "question": "I never apprehensive --- my success.",
      "options": ["for", "of", "at", "with"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 283,
      "question": "Find the correct synonym of the word 'discontented'.",
      "options": ["contented", "happy", "satisfied", "joyful", "miserable"],
      "answer": "miserable"
    },
    {
      "id": 284,
      "question": "Which one is dissimilar ?",
      "options": ["Thought", "Asc", "Into", "But"],
      "answer": "Into"
    },
    {
      "id": 285,
      "question": "Choose the best synonym for the words. World War-2 \"broke out\" in 1939.",
      "options": ["Finished", "Started", "Became worse", "Was cancelled"],
      "answer": "Started"
    },
    {
      "id": 286,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Sympathy' ?",
      "options": ["Antipathetic", "Antipathy", "Adversity", "Oppose"],
      "answer": "Antipathy"
    },
    {
      "id": 287,
      "question": "It is difficult to part ---- a long held belief.",
      "options": ["from", "for", "up", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 288,
      "question": "The ability to tell interesting stories makes one -",
      "options": ["An intrepreneur", "A connoisseur", "A raconteur", "A dandy"],
      "answer": "A raconteur"
    },
    {
      "id": 289,
      "question": "'I never interfere ---- my grown up children,' Mrs. Chowdhury said.",
      "options": ["in", "with", "about", "at"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 290,
      "question": "To foresee is to -",
      "options": ["Remember", "Forget", "See four of something", "Anticipate"],
      "answer": "Anticipate"
    },
    {
      "id": 291,
      "question": "Currently the banking sector is one of --- largest job providers in Bangladesh.",
      "options": [
        "the",
        "credit",
        "financial",
        "remuneration",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "the"
    },
    {
      "id": 292,
      "question": "Choose the right set of would for the blank: Kajal returned ---- London--- plane ---- Dhaka.",
      "options": [
        "in , by , from",
        "from , by , to",
        "to , by , from",
        "at , by , in"
      ],
      "answer": "to , by , from"
    },
    {
      "id": 293,
      "question": "----- the letter tonight,she will post it tomorrow.",
      "options": ["To finish", "Finishing", "Finish", "Finished"],
      "answer": "Finishing"
    },
    {
      "id": 294,
      "question": "A fair little girl sat under a tree. Here preposition is ----?",
      "options": ["fair", "little girl", "under", "tree"],
      "answer": "under"
    },
    {
      "id": 295,
      "question": "He is superior --- me.",
      "options": ["than", "with", "to", "of"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 296,
      "question": "Julia has been ill ---- three months.",
      "options": ["since", "about", "in", "for"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 297,
      "question": "Choose the correct synonym for 'Embezzle'.",
      "options": ["Impede", "Usurp", "Wield", "Defalcate"],
      "answer": "Usurp"
    },
    {
      "id": 298,
      "question": "What would be the right synonym for initiative?",
      "options": ["Apathy", "Indolence", "Enterprise", "Activity"],
      "answer": "Enterprise"
    },
    {
      "id": 299,
      "question": "'Bizarre' means -",
      "options": ["Strange", "Calamity", "Fatal", "Naive"],
      "answer": "Strange"
    },
    {
      "id": 300,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'Authentic' is -",
      "options": ["Correct", "Genuine", "Real", "Exact", "True"],
      "answer": "Genuine"
    },
    {
      "id": 301,
      "question": "They worked hard to complete the task --- time.",
      "options": ["on", "in", "within", "by"],
      "answer": "within"
    },
    {
      "id": 302,
      "question": "'Stalwart' means in politics -",
      "options": [
        "Bad supporter",
        "Reliable supporter",
        "Light supporter",
        "No supporter"
      ],
      "answer": "Reliable supporter"
    },
    {
      "id": 303,
      "question": "He is absorbed ---- throught. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["to", "in", "at", "for"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 304,
      "question": "The burglar jumped --- the compound wall. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["on", "at", "over", "in"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 305,
      "question": "It was a bungled effort to restore order. 'Bungled' here means -",
      "options": ["United", "Unsuccessful", "Unprecedented", "Understated"],
      "answer": "Unsuccessful"
    },
    {
      "id": 306,
      "question": "I still adhere ----- my BCS preposition.",
      "options": ["to", "with", "in", "for"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 307,
      "question": "The opposite word ' Sluggish' -",
      "options": ["Animated", "Dull", "Heavy", "Slow"],
      "answer": "Animated"
    },
    {
      "id": 308,
      "question": "The antonym for 'Recalcitrant' is -",
      "options": ["Compliant", "Passive", "Indifferent", "Careful"],
      "answer": "Compliant"
    },
    {
      "id": 309,
      "question": "The ship was scuttled কথাটির অর্থ হলো -",
      "options": [
        "জাহাজটিতে বোমা নিক্ষেপ করা হলো",
        "জাহাজটি ডুবানো হলো",
        "জাহাজটিতে আগুন লাগানো হলো",
        "জাহাজটি মেরামত করা হলো"
      ],
      "answer": "জাহাজটি ডুবানো হলো"
    },
    {
      "id": 310,
      "question": "Something bought cheaply or for less than usual price is called -",
      "options": [
        "A bargain",
        "An inheritance",
        "A reward",
        "A refund",
        "An interest"
      ],
      "answer": "A bargain"
    },
    {
      "id": 311,
      "question": "Who will account ---- the loss?",
      "options": ["at", "of", "for", "about"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 312,
      "question": "The teacher made the children --- the book.",
      "options": ["read", "to read", "reading", "reads"],
      "answer": "read"
    },
    {
      "id": 313,
      "question": "He has an antipathy ---- smoking.",
      "options": ["for", "to", "with", "in"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 314,
      "question": "Choose the best translation of ' কর্তৃপক্ষ তাকে তিরস্কার করল' from the alternatives below ----?",
      "options": [
        "The authorities criticised him",
        "The authorities took him to book",
        "The authorities gave reins to him",
        "The authorities took him to task"
      ],
      "answer": "The authorities took him to task"
    },
    {
      "id": 315,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Soothe' is -",
      "options": ["Calm", "Secluded", "Irritated", "Sound"],
      "answer": "Irritated"
    },
    {
      "id": 316,
      "question": "The antonym for 'Bonafide' -",
      "options": ["Honest", "Spacious", "Nauseous", "Similar"],
      "answer": "Nauseous"
    },
    {
      "id": 317,
      "question": "I don't mind --- with the cooking but I am not going to wash the dishes.",
      "options": ["to help", "help", "helping", "for help"],
      "answer": "helping"
    },
    {
      "id": 318,
      "question": "The comparison of unlike things using the words like on as is known to be -",
      "options": ["Metaphor", "Simile", "Alliteration", "Personification"],
      "answer": "Simile"
    },
    {
      "id": 319,
      "question": "Magnify is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Forgive", "Extract", "Reduce", "Electrify"],
      "answer": "Reduce"
    },
    {
      "id": 320,
      "question": "Judge found him guilty --- murder.",
      "options": ["for", "with", "of", "against"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 321,
      "question": "We recently entered --- an agreement with the inland co-operative society.",
      "options": ["No preposition", "Upon", "In", "Into"],
      "answer": "Into"
    },
    {
      "id": 322,
      "question": "He was guilty --- contempt of court.",
      "options": ["of", "at", "for", "to"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 323,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Insular' ?",
      "options": ["Interfering", "Open-minded", "Helpful", "Closed"],
      "answer": "Closed"
    },
    {
      "id": 324,
      "question": "The word ''precedence'' means",
      "options": ["Example", "Priority", "Elderly", "Case"],
      "answer": "Priority"
    },
    {
      "id": 325,
      "question": "The phrase “Achilles’ heel” means:",
      "options": [
        "A strong point",
        "A weak point",
        "A permanent solution",
        "A serious idea"
      ],
      "answer": "A weak point"
    },
    {
      "id": 326,
      "question": "Which one in the antonym of 'Ebb' ?",
      "options": ["End", "Downfall", "Flow", "Rapid"],
      "answer": "Flow"
    },
    {
      "id": 327,
      "question": "One day 'women will have what has so long been denied them - leisure, money and room to themselves.",
      "options": ["Space", "Liberty", "Office", "Capacity"],
      "answer": "Liberty"
    },
    {
      "id": 328,
      "question": "The presence of students is important --- Here",
      "options": [
        "Subject differs from verb",
        "Subject agrees with verb",
        "Subject and verb do not go together",
        "Subject is in plural number"
      ],
      "answer": "Subject agrees with verb"
    },
    {
      "id": 329,
      "question": "Choose the right meaning of the word 'generous'",
      "options": ["Willing to give", "Kind", "Honest", "Sympathetic"],
      "answer": "Willing to give"
    },
    {
      "id": 330,
      "question": "We kept notes of everything that ''transpired'' at the meeting. (Synonym)",
      "options": ["Decided", "Recorded", "Happened", "Finished", "Started"],
      "answer": "Happened"
    },
    {
      "id": 331,
      "question": "'Hideously' means -",
      "options": ["Stealthily", "Quietly", "Horribly", "Dangerously"],
      "answer": "Horribly"
    },
    {
      "id": 332,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Disparity' ?",
      "options": ["Argumentation", "Difference", "Belittlement", "Harmony"],
      "answer": "Difference"
    },
    {
      "id": 333,
      "question": "The winter has set ---- very early this year.",
      "options": ["Out", "Off", "Up", "In"],
      "answer": "In"
    },
    {
      "id": 334,
      "question": "Where ------?",
      "options": [
        "Did you cut your hair ?",
        "Have you cut your hair ?",
        "Did you cut your hair ?",
        "Did you have your hair cut ?"
      ],
      "answer": "Did you have your hair cut ?"
    },
    {
      "id": 335,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Belligerent' is -",
      "options": ["Hostile", "Amicable", "Hospitable", "Friendly"],
      "answer": "Hostile"
    },
    {
      "id": 336,
      "question": "Anything 'Pernicious' tends to injure or destroy. Something which has no such harmful effect",
      "options": ["Innocuous", "Innocent", "Immaculate", "Salutary"],
      "answer": "Innocuous"
    },
    {
      "id": 337,
      "question": "The expression browbeating means -",
      "options": [
        "Raising eyebrows",
        "Showing indifference",
        "Showing surprise",
        "Frightening somebody"
      ],
      "answer": "Frightening somebody"
    },
    {
      "id": 338,
      "question": "Select the right word for 'A speech made without previous preparation'",
      "options": [
        "Extempore speech",
        "Memorised speech",
        "Instant speech",
        "Composed speech"
      ],
      "answer": "Extempore speech"
    },
    {
      "id": 339,
      "question": "Select the word you think is closest in meaning to the word 'Antiquated'. Those 'Antiquated' machineries have a huge impact on the current productivity of the firm.",
      "options": [
        "Outdated",
        "Modern",
        "Simple to run",
        "Complex",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Outdated"
    },
    {
      "id": 340,
      "question": "Choose the appropriate preposition to fill in the gap in the following sentence: He fell ---- his bike.",
      "options": ["of", "into", "off", "upon"],
      "answer": "off"
    },
    {
      "id": 341,
      "question": "Candor এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["Diplomacy", "Admire", "Frankness", "Selfish"],
      "answer": "Frankness"
    },
    {
      "id": 342,
      "question": "'Attempt' means -",
      "options": ["Serve", "Try", "Explored", "Explain"],
      "answer": "Try"
    },
    {
      "id": 343,
      "question": "'Ineffable' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Dictatable", "Separable", "Cogent", "Definable", "Ethereal"],
      "answer": "Definable"
    },
    {
      "id": 344,
      "question": "Synonym of 'resuscitate' -",
      "options": ["Regain", "Remark", "Revived", "Return"],
      "answer": "Revived"
    },
    {
      "id": 345,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the expression 'Stanch'",
      "options": ["To reinforce", "Be weak", "Smooth out", "Put an end to"],
      "answer": "Put an end to"
    },
    {
      "id": 346,
      "question": "In TV terms, the opposite of live is -",
      "options": ["Dead", "Asleep", "On the air", "Taped"],
      "answer": "Taped"
    },
    {
      "id": 347,
      "question": "The opposite word of 'Discrete' is -",
      "options": ["Orderly", "Joking", "Famous", "Grouped"],
      "answer": "Grouped"
    },
    {
      "id": 348,
      "question": "The word is 'imbibe' -",
      "options": ["To learn", "To tinge", "To drink", "To acquire"],
      "answer": "To drink"
    },
    {
      "id": 349,
      "question": "Give the antonym of the word 'Ascend'",
      "options": ["Go up", "Stop", "Move away", "Go down"],
      "answer": "Go down"
    },
    {
      "id": 350,
      "question": "'De facto' means -",
      "options": ["As per facts", "In reality", "By rights", "Evidence"],
      "answer": "In reality"
    },
    {
      "id": 351,
      "question": "Give the meaning of the word. The painter decided to 'Exhibit' his work in a gallery.",
      "options": ["Paint", "Show publicly", "Sell", "Present"],
      "answer": "Show publicly"
    },
    {
      "id": 352,
      "question": "I told him everything lest he ----?",
      "options": [
        "Misunderstood me",
        "Should misunderstand me",
        "Should not misunderstand me",
        "Misunderstand me"
      ],
      "answer": "Should misunderstand me"
    },
    {
      "id": 353,
      "question": "The machinery --- working well.",
      "options": ["is", "were", "are", "should"],
      "answer": "is"
    },
    {
      "id": 354,
      "question": "Property inherited from one's father or ancestors -",
      "options": ["Alimony", "Patrimony", "Legacy", "Inheritance"],
      "answer": "Patrimony"
    },
    {
      "id": 355,
      "question": "'Dangerous' means -",
      "options": ["Pleasant", "Risky", "Tedious", "Boring"],
      "answer": "Risky"
    },
    {
      "id": 356,
      "question": "'Equivocation' means ----",
      "options": [
        "A true statement",
        "Equal opportunity to get a job",
        "Free expression of opinion",
        "Two contrary things in the same statement"
      ],
      "answer": "Two contrary things in the same statement"
    },
    {
      "id": 357,
      "question": "The word 'Impediment' is a synonym for:",
      "options": ["Obstacle", "Impertinent", "Embankment", "Progress"],
      "answer": "Obstacle"
    },
    {
      "id": 358,
      "question": "Choose the word that means the opposite of 'reluctantly' ?",
      "options": ["Unwillingly", "Not willing", "Eagerly", "Not eagerly"],
      "answer": "Eagerly"
    },
    {
      "id": 359,
      "question": "Father put --- some amount of money for the education of his daughter.",
      "options": ["up", "aside", "into", "on"],
      "answer": "aside"
    },
    {
      "id": 360,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'Vice versa'?",
      "options": [
        "For example",
        "Face to face",
        "Namely",
        "The terms being exchanged"
      ],
      "answer": "The terms being exchanged"
    },
    {
      "id": 361,
      "question": "Choose the correct meaning of 'Vanquish'",
      "options": ["Poor", "Conquer", "Defeat", "Discard"],
      "answer": "Conquer"
    },
    {
      "id": 362,
      "question": "Syntax denotes ---",
      "options": [
        "Rules for writing paragraph",
        "Rules for sentence building",
        "Rules for correct pronunciation",
        "Rules for writing an essay"
      ],
      "answer": "Rules for sentence building"
    },
    {
      "id": 363,
      "question": "He is afflicted --- gout.",
      "options": ["to", "of", "on", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 364,
      "question": "My birthday is --- February.",
      "options": ["in", "on", "at", "by"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 365,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'orthodoxy' ?",
      "options": [
        "Renown",
        "Trepidation",
        "Unconventionality",
        "Inquisitiveness",
        "Remoteness"
      ],
      "answer": "Unconventionality"
    },
    {
      "id": 366,
      "question": "The word 'posterity' means",
      "options": [
        "Later generation",
        "Prosperity",
        "Present time",
        "Past days"
      ],
      "answer": "Later generation"
    },
    {
      "id": 367,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym for 'Cynical'",
      "options": ["Pessimistic", "Gullible", "Equivocal", "Liberal"],
      "answer": "Gullible"
    },
    {
      "id": 368,
      "question": "Choose the correct sentence",
      "options": [
        "Scarcely had we started than is began to rain",
        "Scarcely had we started when it began to rain",
        "Scarcely had we started but it started to rain",
        "Scarcely had we been started but it began to rain"
      ],
      "answer": "Scarcely had we started when it began to rain"
    },
    {
      "id": 369,
      "question": "My friend ---- yesterday.",
      "options": [
        "got his car repaired",
        "gets his car repaired",
        "got his car repair",
        "have got his car repaired"
      ],
      "answer": "got his car repaired"
    },
    {
      "id": 370,
      "question": "He was conspicuous by his absence:",
      "options": ["Suspicious", "Famous", "Focused", "Singled out"],
      "answer": "Singled out"
    },
    {
      "id": 371,
      "question": "Fate smiles ---- those who untriedly grapple with stark realities of life.",
      "options": ["with", "over", "on", "round"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 372,
      "question": "Which phrase contains words opposed to each other in meaning ?",
      "options": [
        "Hopes and aspirations",
        "Heat and dust",
        "Reproduction and death",
        "Emerged and advanced"
      ],
      "answer": "Reproduction and death"
    },
    {
      "id": 373,
      "question": "The word 'disinterested'' means",
      "options": ["Lack of interest", "Indifferent", "Callous", "Neutral"],
      "answer": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "id": 374,
      "question": "Something given or done as an expression of esteem:",
      "options": [
        "Verbatim",
        "Stampede",
        "Tribute",
        "Lullaby",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Tribute"
    },
    {
      "id": 375,
      "question": "God took pity ---- him.",
      "options": ["on", "into", "over", "with"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 376,
      "question": "Give the synonym of 'Conjugal'",
      "options": ["Bridal", "Approval", "Deadly", "Disputable"],
      "answer": "Bridal"
    },
    {
      "id": 377,
      "question": "Which one is a reptile ?",
      "options": ["Colt", "Anaconda", "Vixen", "Boar"],
      "answer": "Anaconda"
    },
    {
      "id": 378,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Hide' is -",
      "options": ["Camouflage", "Deception", "Disguised", "Mask"],
      "answer": "Mask"
    },
    {
      "id": 379,
      "question": "One who is a specialist in the heart and its diseases is -",
      "options": [
        "A pharmacologist",
        "A cardiologist",
        "An optician",
        "A neurologist"
      ],
      "answer": "A cardiologist"
    },
    {
      "id": 380,
      "question": "Mr. Ahad 'seized' the opportunity to present the proposal to the director -",
      "options": ["Realized", "Grasped", "Rendered", "Delivered"],
      "answer": "Grasped"
    },
    {
      "id": 381,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Indifference' is ----",
      "options": ["Ardour", "Compassion", "Anxiety", "Concern"],
      "answer": "Ardour"
    },
    {
      "id": 382,
      "question": "'Optimist' means ---",
      "options": ["আশাবাদী ব্যক্তি", "দর্শন", "দার্শনিক", "জগৎই শ্রেষ্ঠ"],
      "answer": "আশাবাদী ব্যক্তি"
    },
    {
      "id": 383,
      "question": "Which is the antonym of the word 'handsome' ?",
      "options": ["Ugly", "Foul", "Bad", "Unpleasant"],
      "answer": "Ugly"
    },
    {
      "id": 384,
      "question": "Select the word you think is closest in meaning to the word 'reciprocity' in the following sentence: Every relation is measured and evaluated on the basis of reciprocity at one point in time.",
      "options": [
        "Reception",
        "Mutual",
        "Reactivity",
        "Sacrifice",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Sacrifice"
    },
    {
      "id": 385,
      "question": "The word 'Shrug' indicating doubt or indifference is associated with -",
      "options": ["Shoulders", "Head", "Forehead", "Eyebrows"],
      "answer": "Shoulders"
    },
    {
      "id": 386,
      "question": "The speaker 'emphasized' the need for cooperation in the project that we were about to undertake -",
      "options": ["Accentuated", "Downplayed", "Discussed", "Displayed"],
      "answer": "Accentuated"
    },
    {
      "id": 387,
      "question": "'Venerate' means -",
      "options": ["Defame", "Abuse", "Respect", "Accuse"],
      "answer": "Respect"
    },
    {
      "id": 388,
      "question": "Which of the following pairs contain correct synonyms?",
      "options": [
        "Practise: Hands-on",
        "Powerful: Leverage",
        "Possibility: Viable",
        "Plan: Platform"
      ],
      "answer": "Powerful: Leverage"
    },
    {
      "id": 389,
      "question": "Graf looked in awesome form as she cruised --- an easy 6-2 , 6-1 victory in the final game.",
      "options": ["on", "over", "ind", "to"],
      "answer": "ind"
    },
    {
      "id": 390,
      "question": "Amenable is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Stubborn", "Docile", "Obedient", "Offensive"],
      "answer": "Stubborn"
    },
    {
      "id": 391,
      "question": "A synonym for 'Mischievous' is -",
      "options": ["Kind", "Serious", "Well-behaved", "Vicious"],
      "answer": "Vicious"
    },
    {
      "id": 392,
      "question": "Choose the one that best expresses the meaning of the given word: Omnipotent",
      "options": ["Feeble", "Supreme", "Impotent", "Vulnerable"],
      "answer": "Supreme"
    },
    {
      "id": 393,
      "question": "The word 'Banish' means",
      "options": ["Exile", "Emerge", "Drive away", "Expel"],
      "answer": "Exile"
    },
    {
      "id": 394,
      "question": "Find out the correct sentence.",
      "options": [
        "I told her everything lest she misunderstands me",
        "I told her everything lest she should misunderstands me",
        "I told her everything lest she will misunderstands me",
        "I told her everything lest she might misunderstands me"
      ],
      "answer": "I told her everything lest she should misunderstands me"
    },
    {
      "id": 395,
      "question": "His house is adjacent ---- mine.",
      "options": ["with", "to", "against", "beside"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 396,
      "question": "Comprehension শব্দের অর্থ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["Loss", "Calamity", "Difference", "Knowledge"],
      "answer": "Knowledge"
    },
    {
      "id": 397,
      "question": "The two companies consolidated --- greater efficiency.",
      "options": ["on", "for", "with", "up"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 398,
      "question": "What do we call a man who controls a game of football ?",
      "options": ["Captain", "Coach", "Goalkeeper", "Referee"],
      "answer": "Referee"
    },
    {
      "id": 399,
      "question": "He was reasonably well-off. A substitute for 'reasonably' is:",
      "options": ["Very", "Extremely", "Exceedingly", "Quite"],
      "answer": "Quite"
    },
    {
      "id": 400,
      "question": "নিম্নে সঠিক sentence কোনটি ?",
      "options": [
        "Will you mind to go there ?",
        "Would you mind going there ?",
        "Will you mind going there ?",
        "Would you mind to go there ?"
      ],
      "answer": "Would you mind going there ?"
    },
    {
      "id": 401,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'Defect'?",
      "options": ["Illegal", "Prodigal", "Defective", "In fact"],
      "answer": "Defective"
    },
    {
      "id": 402,
      "question": "Would you be so kind ----- to keep me informed?",
      "options": ["that", "enough", "as", "much"],
      "answer": "as"
    },
    {
      "id": 403,
      "question": "Choose the best synonym for the word. What are those boys talking about ? I wonder what they are 'up to' -",
      "options": [
        "Standing on",
        "Climbing up",
        "Planning to do",
        "Arguing about"
      ],
      "answer": "Planning to do"
    },
    {
      "id": 404,
      "question": "The policeman rescued the child ---- danger.",
      "options": ["of", "from", "on", "at"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 405,
      "question": "Panacea -এর সমার্থক -",
      "options": ["oanake", "praise", "inactivity", "cure all"],
      "answer": "cure all"
    },
    {
      "id": 406,
      "question": "The man --- in the accident was taken to the hospital?",
      "options": ["injured", "has injured", "being injured", "who injured"],
      "answer": "who injured"
    },
    {
      "id": 407,
      "question": "A free-lance journalist is -",
      "options": [
        "An independent journalist",
        "An unpaid journalist",
        "A journalist belonging to another country",
        "An unqualified journalist"
      ],
      "answer": "An independent journalist"
    },
    {
      "id": 408,
      "question": "What is the opposite word of 'Optimist' ?",
      "options": ["Pessimist", "Despair", "Negative", "Desire"],
      "answer": "Pessimist"
    },
    {
      "id": 409,
      "question": "Windfall - এর অর্থ কি ?",
      "options": ["ঝড়", "অপ্রত্যাশিতভাবে পাওয়া সুফল", "বন্যা", "জলোচ্ছ্বাস"],
      "answer": "অপ্রত্যাশিতভাবে পাওয়া সুফল"
    },
    {
      "id": 410,
      "question": "Love for mankind is called--",
      "options": ["Philanthropy", "Androphile", "Philology", "Philosopher"],
      "answer": "Philanthropy"
    },
    {
      "id": 411,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Jovial' ?",
      "options": ["Jolly", "Gay", "Jealous", "Happy"],
      "answer": "Happy"
    },
    {
      "id": 412,
      "question": "Replace the words by a single adjective: Airline pilots undergo 'Very stricts and severe health checks' at regular intervals.",
      "options": ["Spontaneous", "Unanimous", "Outrageous", "Rigorous"],
      "answer": "Rigorous"
    },
    {
      "id": 413,
      "question": "Honesty is the best policy. এখানে 'honesty' হচ্ছে ?",
      "options": [
        "Proper Noun",
        "Common Noun",
        "Collective Noun",
        "Abstract Noun"
      ],
      "answer": "Abstract Noun"
    },
    {
      "id": 414,
      "question": "The correct antonym of the word 'Shrivel' is -",
      "options": ["Embrace", "Expand", "Explode", "Enslave"],
      "answer": "Expand"
    },
    {
      "id": 415,
      "question": "Choose the right form of the verb: I have the (little) money ?",
      "options": ["Slightest", "Little", "Least", "Less"],
      "answer": "Least"
    },
    {
      "id": 416,
      "question": "Fahim was looking to the authority for the confirmation of his status.",
      "options": ["Forward", "Inc", "Into", "Around", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Forward"
    },
    {
      "id": 417,
      "question": "He parted --- his friends in tears.",
      "options": ["with", "from", "against", "beside"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 418,
      "question": "Sonia has been sick ---- two months.",
      "options": ["from", "for", "since", "about"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 419,
      "question": "The profession of teaching ---",
      "options": ["Pedagogy", "History", "Linguistic", "Teachership"],
      "answer": "Pedagogy"
    },
    {
      "id": 420,
      "question": "He would have my support in a heartbeat. Here 'Heartbeat' means -",
      "options": ["Automatically", "In no time", "Naturally", "Imminently"],
      "answer": "In no time"
    },
    {
      "id": 421,
      "question": "This children's park -- half an hour before sunset.",
      "options": ["Opens", "Starts", "Closes", "Stops"],
      "answer": "Closes"
    },
    {
      "id": 422,
      "question": "Select the word closest in meaning to the word-শিক্ষিত",
      "options": ["Gentleman", "Generous", "Educated", "Pious"],
      "answer": "Educated"
    },
    {
      "id": 423,
      "question": "I can hear someone ---",
      "options": [
        "to scream",
        "scream",
        "screaming",
        "for screaming",
        "screamed"
      ],
      "answer": "scream"
    },
    {
      "id": 424,
      "question": "It --- when I reached home. বাক্যটির জন্য নিম্নে প্রদত্ত সঠিক verb form নির্বাচন করে বাক্য পুরন্নকরুন।",
      "options": [
        "Was raining",
        "Is raining",
        "Has been raining",
        "Had raining"
      ],
      "answer": "Was raining"
    },
    {
      "id": 425,
      "question": "'CANDID' is most nearly similar in meaning to -",
      "options": ["Vague", "Outspoken", "Experienced", "Anxious"],
      "answer": "Outspoken"
    },
    {
      "id": 426,
      "question": "I shall adhere ----- my plan.",
      "options": ["in", "at", "about", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 427,
      "question": "I acceded --- his request. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["on", "at", "for", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 428,
      "question": "A cobbler is a person who -",
      "options": [
        "Sells shoes",
        "Mends shoes",
        "Collects shoes",
        "Makes shoes"
      ],
      "answer": "Mends shoes"
    },
    {
      "id": 429,
      "question": "The results were inconclusive. 'Inconclusive' means -",
      "options": ["Intricate", "Complex", "Incomplete", "Not defined"],
      "answer": "Not defined"
    },
    {
      "id": 430,
      "question": "Which one completes the sentence properly? Some days --- since my father died.",
      "options": ["Are passed", "Passed", "Have passed", "Had passed"],
      "answer": "Have passed"
    },
    {
      "id": 431,
      "question": "Which word is not a noun ?",
      "options": ["Articulation", "Simulation", "Defamed", "Indemnity"],
      "answer": "Defamed"
    },
    {
      "id": 432,
      "question": "'Dissent' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Agreement", "Dispute", "Disunity", "Controversy"],
      "answer": "Agreement"
    },
    {
      "id": 433,
      "question": "'Nostalgic' is the synonym of -",
      "options": ["Soothing", "Homesick", "Diseased", "Indolent"],
      "answer": "Homesick"
    },
    {
      "id": 434,
      "question": "Julian spent most of his holiday in the bathroom. He ate some seafood that did not agree --- him.",
      "options": ["On", "To", "With", "About"],
      "answer": "With"
    },
    {
      "id": 435,
      "question": "Put the verb in the correct form --",
      "options": ["Are covered", "Is covered", "Had covered", "Have covered"],
      "answer": "Is covered"
    },
    {
      "id": 436,
      "question": "Which one is the right in use ?",
      "options": [
        "It is no good of to talk to him",
        "To talk him is of no good",
        "It's no use talking to him",
        "It's of no use how talking to him"
      ],
      "answer": "It's no use talking to him"
    },
    {
      "id": 437,
      "question": "If you are forbidden to do something, 'it mean you need not to do it'.",
      "options": [
        "It means you are not do it",
        "It means you must not do it",
        "It means you could do it",
        "It means you have not go to do it",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "It means you must not do it"
    },
    {
      "id": 438,
      "question": "Almost everyone fails --- on the first try.",
      "options": [
        "in passing his drivers test",
        "to have passed his drivers test",
        "to his drivers test",
        "passing his drivers test"
      ],
      "answer": "in passing his drivers test"
    },
    {
      "id": 439,
      "question": "----- discovery of insulin, it was not possible to treat diabetes.",
      "options": ["Prior", "To prior", "Prior to the", "The prior"],
      "answer": "Prior to the"
    },
    {
      "id": 440,
      "question": "Choose the word that means the opposite of 'pacify' -",
      "options": ["expose", "arouse", "separate", "comfort", "deny"],
      "answer": "arouse"
    },
    {
      "id": 441,
      "question": "'Eternal vigilance is the price of liberty' Here 'eternal' refers to -",
      "options": ["temporary", "obvious", "vigilant", "everlasting"],
      "answer": "everlasting"
    },
    {
      "id": 442,
      "question": "A reward has been announced for the employees who --- hard.",
      "options": [
        "have worked",
        "has worked",
        "will be worked",
        "have had worked"
      ],
      "answer": "have worked"
    },
    {
      "id": 443,
      "question": "'Feed the baby ---- milk' বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["to", "in", "on", "with"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 444,
      "question": "He deals in rice but does not know how to deal --- the customers.",
      "options": ["to", "of", "with", "for"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 445,
      "question": "Choose the word which most nearly similar in meaning of 'anxiously' -",
      "options": ["Worriedly", "Unhappily", "Slowly", "Hastily"],
      "answer": "Worriedly"
    },
    {
      "id": 446,
      "question": "I had to go to Dhaka ----- my sister's marriage.",
      "options": ["because", "due to", "because of", "as"],
      "answer": "because of"
    },
    {
      "id": 447,
      "question": "Opposite of 'Help' is --",
      "options": ["Hinder", "Replace", "Rise", "Work"],
      "answer": "Hinder"
    },
    {
      "id": 448,
      "question": "The antonym for 'Inimical' is -",
      "options": ["Hostile", "Friendly", "Indifferent", "Angry"],
      "answer": "Friendly"
    },
    {
      "id": 449,
      "question": "To resolve a problem is to --",
      "options": [
        "Find an answer",
        "Ignore it",
        "Pose a question",
        "Do mathematics"
      ],
      "answer": "Find an answer"
    },
    {
      "id": 450,
      "question": "Abraham Lincons -- one of the great men of american history.",
      "options": ["was", "is", "had been", "will be", "None"],
      "answer": "was"
    },
    {
      "id": 451,
      "question": "The novelist is observant --- public feeling.",
      "options": ["with", "against", "of", "for"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 452,
      "question": "Many islands make up --",
      "options": ["An isle", "An archipelago", "A peninsula", "A continent"],
      "answer": "An archipelago"
    },
    {
      "id": 453,
      "question": "The expression 'take into account' means",
      "options": ["Count numbers", "Consider", "Think seriously", "Assess"],
      "answer": "Consider"
    },
    {
      "id": 454,
      "question": "'Morbid' means -",
      "options": [
        "Gruesome",
        "Dead",
        "A place to keep dead bodies",
        "Tranquilizer"
      ],
      "answer": "Gruesome"
    },
    {
      "id": 455,
      "question": "What kind of noun is 'fun' ?",
      "options": ["Countable", "Uncountable", "Common", "Material"],
      "answer": "Uncountable"
    },
    {
      "id": 456,
      "question": "The word 'Revoke' means",
      "options": ["To go back", "To call back", "To call in", "To move"],
      "answer": "To call in"
    },
    {
      "id": 457,
      "question": "He knows and speaks many languages. Choose the appropriate sentence that best matches the above description.",
      "options": [
        "He is an interpreter",
        "He is a polyglot",
        "He is an infidel",
        "He is a tycoon"
      ],
      "answer": "He is a polyglot"
    },
    {
      "id": 458,
      "question": "Choose the correct answer: Would you mind (take) simply a cup of tea?",
      "options": ["to take", "taken", "taking", "to have taken"],
      "answer": "taking"
    },
    {
      "id": 459,
      "question": "The gory scenes were off-putting.A substitute of 'gory' is -",
      "options": ["Blood-curdling", "Glorious", "Garbled", "Quiet"],
      "answer": "Blood-curdling"
    },
    {
      "id": 460,
      "question": "I stretched for tissue but the box of tissues --- nearly empty.",
      "options": ["was", "were", "has", "have", "None of these"],
      "answer": "was"
    },
    {
      "id": 461,
      "question": "Complete the sentence with a suitable word: Ahraj ran fast lest he --- miss the class.",
      "options": ["could", "should", "would", "can"],
      "answer": "should"
    },
    {
      "id": 462,
      "question": "He divided the money --- the two children.",
      "options": ["over", "in between", "among", "between"],
      "answer": "between"
    },
    {
      "id": 463,
      "question": "Complete the sentence : I will phone you when I ---- the news.",
      "options": ["am getting", "get", "will get", "will be getting"],
      "answer": "get"
    },
    {
      "id": 464,
      "question": "An atheist is aperson who -",
      "options": [
        "Does not believe in god",
        "Believes in god",
        "Hates god",
        "Loves god"
      ],
      "answer": "Does not believe in god"
    },
    {
      "id": 465,
      "question": "'Enlarge' means -",
      "options": ["shrink", "large", "contract", "slip", "expand"],
      "answer": "expand"
    },
    {
      "id": 466,
      "question": "I was a admitted --- Dhaka College. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["in", "to", "from", "on"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 467,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Vigilant' is -",
      "options": ["Tired", "Fickle", "Wicked", "Watchful", "Steady"],
      "answer": "Watchful"
    },
    {
      "id": 468,
      "question": "I prefer tea --- coffee.",
      "options": ["for", "than", "from", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 469,
      "question": "The synonyms for 'Corrective' is -",
      "options": ["Righteous", "Preventive", "Prohibitive", "Remedial"],
      "answer": "Remedial"
    },
    {
      "id": 470,
      "question": "Pilferage' is a soft word for",
      "options": ["Stealing", "Pillar", "Pilgrimage", "Piled up"],
      "answer": "Stealing"
    },
    {
      "id": 471,
      "question": "The weight was too much and the pillar gave way . Here 'gave way' indicates -",
      "options": ["Bent down", "Was changed", "Was broken", "Vanished"],
      "answer": "Was broken"
    },
    {
      "id": 472,
      "question": "The word 'paranoid' is connected with -",
      "options": ["Philosophy", "Psychology", "Anthropology", "Theology"],
      "answer": "Psychology"
    },
    {
      "id": 473,
      "question": "'Amalgamate' is the antonym of -",
      "options": ["Generate", "Repair", "Materialise", "Separate"],
      "answer": "Separate"
    },
    {
      "id": 474,
      "question": "Antonym of 'Rectify' is -",
      "options": ["Apologize", "Make worse", "Rebuke", "Correct"],
      "answer": "Make worse"
    },
    {
      "id": 475,
      "question": "One who unduly forwards in rendering services foe others is not generally liked in society. Which of the following words represents truely the character of the person mentioned above?",
      "options": ["Benevolent", "Official", "Officious", "Bureaucratic"],
      "answer": "Officious"
    },
    {
      "id": 476,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Consessus' -",
      "options": [
        "Disagreement",
        "Conclusion",
        "Conscious",
        "General agreement"
      ],
      "answer": "General agreement"
    },
    {
      "id": 477,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Bold'?",
      "options": ["Brave", "Hard", "Sunny", "Mild"],
      "answer": "Brave"
    },
    {
      "id": 478,
      "question": "Do not impute motives ---- him.",
      "options": ["to", "in", "on", "against"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 479,
      "question": "What is the meaning of 'six of ,one and half a dozen of another' ?",
      "options": [
        "Twelve pieces",
        "Negligible difference",
        "Thoroughly",
        "Countless"
      ],
      "answer": "Negligible difference"
    },
    {
      "id": 480,
      "question": "The synonym for 'Bonafide' is -",
      "options": ["Artificial", "Permanent", "Imaginary", "Genuine"],
      "answer": "Genuine"
    },
    {
      "id": 481,
      "question": "Even as harvesting was going on.",
      "options": [
        "the rainy season began",
        "the rainy season was began",
        "the rainy season had began",
        "the rainy season began"
      ],
      "answer": "the rainy season began"
    },
    {
      "id": 482,
      "question": "The meaning of the phrase 'turn up' in the sentence 'He never turns up on time for meetings' is -",
      "options": ["Looks forward to", "Takes a turn", "Stands up", "Arrives"],
      "answer": "Arrives"
    },
    {
      "id": 483,
      "question": "The house ablaze is next door to mine. In this sentence 'ablaze' means -",
      "options": ["Glowing", "Burning", "Lightening", "Colourful"],
      "answer": "Burning"
    },
    {
      "id": 484,
      "question": "\"Syntax\" means ---",
      "options": [
        "Manner of speech",
        "Sentence building",
        "Supplementary tax",
        "Synchronizing act"
      ],
      "answer": "Sentence building"
    },
    {
      "id": 485,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'Homogeneous' ?",
      "options": ["Heterogeneous", "Scrambled", "Motley", "Similar"],
      "answer": "Similar"
    },
    {
      "id": 486,
      "question": "God is good --- me. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["with", "at", "on", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 487,
      "question": "The word 'Omniscient' means --",
      "options": [
        "One who knows everything",
        "One who has total power",
        "One who is present everywhere",
        "One who eats all types of food"
      ],
      "answer": "One who knows everything"
    },
    {
      "id": 488,
      "question": "He watched the mist ascending --- the valley.",
      "options": ["through", "from", "in", "within"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 489,
      "question": "FERTILE is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Useful", "Barren", "Gloomy", "Isolated"],
      "answer": "Barren"
    },
    {
      "id": 490,
      "question": "'Adversity' means",
      "options": ["Failure", "Helplessness", "Misfortune", "Crisis"],
      "answer": "Misfortune"
    },
    {
      "id": 491,
      "question": "He is a hard nut to crack - বাক্যটির সঠিক বাংলা অনুবাদঃ",
      "options": [
        "সে বড় পাগল লোক",
        "সে বড় চুর লোক",
        "সে বড় শক্ত লোক",
        "সে বড় দুর্বল লোক"
      ],
      "answer": "সে বড় দুর্বল লোক"
    },
    {
      "id": 492,
      "question": "What is the correct synonym of 'Isolation' ?",
      "options": ["Loneliness", "Separation", "Depression", "Sadness"],
      "answer": "Separation"
    },
    {
      "id": 493,
      "question": "My father never approved of --- a foreigner.",
      "options": [
        "her to marry",
        "her marrying",
        "she marrying",
        "she to marry"
      ],
      "answer": "her marrying"
    },
    {
      "id": 494,
      "question": "The word 'Magnificent' means",
      "options": ["Splendid", "Resourceful", "Thoughtful", "Disgraceful"],
      "answer": "Splendid"
    },
    {
      "id": 495,
      "question": "When water ---- , it turn into ice.",
      "options": ["freezes", "will freeze", "would freeze", "froze"],
      "answer": "freezes"
    },
    {
      "id": 496,
      "question": "You are looking smart --- this dress.",
      "options": ["on", "in", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 497,
      "question": "'Temporal' means",
      "options": ["Temporary", "Tempting", "Religious", "Worldly"],
      "answer": "Worldly"
    },
    {
      "id": 498,
      "question": "Your offer is acceptable --- me. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["by", "on", "for", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 499,
      "question": "Correct synonym of the word 'Ignite' -",
      "options": ["Kindle", "To set fire", "To burn", "To burn fire"],
      "answer": "Kindle"
    },
    {
      "id": 500,
      "question": "The Thames ---- London.",
      "options": ["flows by", "flows from", "flows into", "flows through"],
      "answer": "flows through"
    },
    {
      "id": 501,
      "question": "The antonym of 'advocate' is -",
      "options": ["define", "oppose", "removed", "support", "discern"],
      "answer": "oppose"
    },
    {
      "id": 502,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Divergence' is -",
      "options": ["Convergence", "Concourse", "Concurrency", "Deviation"],
      "answer": "Deviation"
    },
    {
      "id": 503,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Implicit' ?",
      "options": ["Explicit", "Introvert", "Spoken", "Tacit"],
      "answer": "Tacit"
    },
    {
      "id": 504,
      "question": "Bibliography means -",
      "options": [
        "History of books",
        "Collection of books",
        "Worshipper of books",
        "Book on biology"
      ],
      "answer": "Collection of books"
    },
    {
      "id": 505,
      "question": "Complete the following sentence with the correct tense : We were watching the news when the telephone ---",
      "options": ["ringing", "had rung", "rang", "rung"],
      "answer": "rang"
    },
    {
      "id": 506,
      "question": "The word 'Capital' relates to -",
      "options": ["Hand", "Head", "Light", "Globe"],
      "answer": "Head"
    },
    {
      "id": 507,
      "question": "Choose the word that is most nearly opposite in meaning to the word 'Exclude' -",
      "options": ["Admit", "Harden", "Review", "Isolate"],
      "answer": "Admit"
    },
    {
      "id": 508,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Optimist' ?",
      "options": ["Pessimist", "Change", "Despair", "Hopeful"],
      "answer": "Hopeful"
    },
    {
      "id": 509,
      "question": "Choose the best synonym for the word. The traffic had to be 'diverted' as a result of a serious accident.",
      "options": [
        "Sent by another route",
        "Slowed down",
        "Stopped completely",
        "Searched by policemen"
      ],
      "answer": "Sent by another route"
    },
    {
      "id": 510,
      "question": "Anatomy শব্দের অর্থ -",
      "options": ["সাদৃশ্য", "স্নায়ুতন্ত্র", "শারীরবিদ্য", "অঙ্গসঞ্চালন"],
      "answer": "শারীরবিদ্য"
    },
    {
      "id": 511,
      "question": "The boy form the village said,'I --- starve than beg; Which of the following best completes the above sentence ?",
      "options": ["better", "rather", "would rather", "would better"],
      "answer": "would rather"
    },
    {
      "id": 512,
      "question": "The word 'officialese' means -",
      "options": [
        "plural number of official",
        "language used in offices",
        "plural number of office",
        "vague expressions"
      ],
      "answer": "language used in offices"
    },
    {
      "id": 513,
      "question": "It's time (you realize) your mistake. Which of the following clauses does best fit in the above sentence ?",
      "options": [
        "You realized",
        "That you realize",
        "You would realize",
        "You have realized"
      ],
      "answer": "You realized"
    },
    {
      "id": 514,
      "question": "He was conspicuos by his absence",
      "options": ["Suspicious", "Famous", "Focused", "Singled out"],
      "answer": "Singled out"
    },
    {
      "id": 515,
      "question": "I was lived that night, I --- wood all morning.",
      "options": ["was cutting", "had been cutting", "had cut", "cut"],
      "answer": "had been cutting"
    },
    {
      "id": 516,
      "question": "Evacuate is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "boil off",
        "fill up",
        "neutralize",
        "melt down",
        "none of these"
      ],
      "answer": "fill up"
    },
    {
      "id": 517,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym for 'Oblige'.",
      "options": ["Bind", "Require", "Bother", "Censure"],
      "answer": "Censure"
    },
    {
      "id": 518,
      "question": "Synonym for 'Temerity' is -",
      "options": ["Sobriety", "Insolence", "Propriety", "Lousy"],
      "answer": "Insolence"
    },
    {
      "id": 519,
      "question": "'Demon' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Charitable", "Kind-hearted", "Angel", "Fair-minded"],
      "answer": "Angel"
    },
    {
      "id": 520,
      "question": "'Mayhem' means -",
      "options": [
        "A bizarre situation",
        "A may day event",
        "Confusion and fear caused by violent behaviour",
        "A sudden collapse"
      ],
      "answer": "Confusion and fear caused by violent behaviour"
    },
    {
      "id": 521,
      "question": "'An extrovert' is a person who -",
      "options": [
        "Likes isolation",
        "Shares his cheerful feelings with others",
        "Behaves like a stoic",
        "Keeps himself aloof from others"
      ],
      "answer": "Shares his cheerful feelings with others"
    },
    {
      "id": 522,
      "question": "He will compensate you ---- the loss.",
      "options": ["of", "to", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 523,
      "question": "The word 'genocide' means",
      "options": [
        "mass grave",
        "mass gathering",
        "mass killing",
        "mass attendance"
      ],
      "answer": "mass killing"
    },
    {
      "id": 524,
      "question": "Malicious is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Boastful", "Indifferent", "Kind", "Arrogant"],
      "answer": "Kind"
    },
    {
      "id": 525,
      "question": "\"What he said is largely true\" means?",
      "options": [
        "What he said is surely true?",
        "What he said is completely true ?",
        "What he said is possibly true?",
        "What he said is mostly true?"
      ],
      "answer": "What he said is mostly true?"
    },
    {
      "id": 526,
      "question": "He has no control ---- himself.",
      "options": ["at", "over", "on", "in"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 527,
      "question": "Choose the one which best expresses the meaning of the given word 'Obscene' ?",
      "options": ["Objectionable", "Indecent", "Displeasing", "Condemnable"],
      "answer": "Indecent"
    },
    {
      "id": 528,
      "question": "Meaning of the word 'Habeas Corpus' is -",
      "options": [
        "Citizen's democratic right",
        "Fundamental rights of prisoners",
        "Freedom of jurisprudence",
        "Withdrawal of embassy"
      ],
      "answer": "Fundamental rights of prisoners"
    },
    {
      "id": 529,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Oblivious' ?",
      "options": ["Aware", "Mindful", "Heedless", "Observant"],
      "answer": "Heedless"
    },
    {
      "id": 530,
      "question": "Choose the synonym of the word 'Deplete' -",
      "options": ["Diminish", "Cease", "Plunder", "Increase"],
      "answer": "Diminish"
    },
    {
      "id": 531,
      "question": "ABERRATION is most nearly similar in meaning to -",
      "options": ["Deviation", "Abhorrence", "Disliked", "Absence"],
      "answer": "Deviation"
    },
    {
      "id": 532,
      "question": "A synonym for 'resentment' is -",
      "options": ["Fear", "Anger", "Panic", "Indignation"],
      "answer": "Anger"
    },
    {
      "id": 533,
      "question": "'Hamlet' means",
      "options": [
        "A small village",
        "A small town",
        "A big city",
        "A big village"
      ],
      "answer": "A small village"
    },
    {
      "id": 534,
      "question": "Identify the correct sentence:",
      "options": [
        "No sooner had we had reached the station the train left",
        "No sooner had we had reached the station then the train left",
        "No sooner had we had reached the train had left",
        "No sooner had we had reached the station than the train left"
      ],
      "answer": "No sooner had we had reached the station than the train left"
    },
    {
      "id": 535,
      "question": "কোনটি 'Panic' শব্দের সমার্থক শব্দ ?",
      "options": ["Serenity", "Horror", "Calmness", "Tranquillity"],
      "answer": "Horror"
    },
    {
      "id": 536,
      "question": "Dull শব্দের অর্থ",
      "options": ["নির্বোধ", "সাহসী", "চালাক", "চতুর"],
      "answer": "নির্বোধ"
    },
    {
      "id": 537,
      "question": "A chart was \"appended\" to the report. here \"appended\" means -",
      "options": ["changed", "removed", "joined", "shortened"],
      "answer": "joined"
    },
    {
      "id": 538,
      "question": "The charge of murder was brought ---- him.",
      "options": ["against", "for", "about", "with"],
      "answer": "against"
    },
    {
      "id": 539,
      "question": "Swimming is conducive ---- health.",
      "options": ["in", "for", "to", "at"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 540,
      "question": "What would be the right synonym for initiative?",
      "options": ["Apathy", "Indolence", "Enterprise", "Activity"],
      "answer": "Enterprise"
    },
    {
      "id": 541,
      "question": "The rebels were put ---- death.",
      "options": ["in", "to", "for", "on"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 542,
      "question": "The Charity of Hatem Tai is known to all . The word 'Charity' is -----?",
      "options": [
        "Material noun",
        "Common noun",
        "Abstract noun",
        "Collective noun"
      ],
      "answer": "Abstract noun"
    },
    {
      "id": 543,
      "question": "She is good ---- lawn tennis.",
      "options": ["at", "on", "in", "for"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 544,
      "question": "'Mishap' means",
      "options": ["Danger", "Disease", "Accident", "Theft"],
      "answer": "Accident"
    },
    {
      "id": 545,
      "question": "'Wisdom' অর্থ কি ?",
      "options": ["বুদ্ধি", "জ্ঞান", "প্রজ্ঞা", "মেধা"],
      "answer": "প্রজ্ঞা"
    },
    {
      "id": 546,
      "question": "A remedy for all diseases:",
      "options": ["Cure", "Panacea", "Panorama", "Polyglote"],
      "answer": "Panacea"
    },
    {
      "id": 547,
      "question": "I count --- your help.",
      "options": ["after", "upon", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "upon"
    },
    {
      "id": 548,
      "question": "Twenty years --- since my father died.",
      "options": ["has passed", "have hoped", "passd", "passed"],
      "answer": "have passed"
    },
    {
      "id": 549,
      "question": "The term 'en route' means -",
      "options": [
        "Through the route",
        "Through the way",
        "On the way",
        "In the way"
      ],
      "answer": "On the way"
    },
    {
      "id": 550,
      "question": "Antonym of 'Harmony' is -",
      "options": ["Admiration", "Co-operation", "Discord", "Co-ordination"],
      "answer": "Discord"
    },
    {
      "id": 551,
      "question": "Words inscribed on a tomb is an -",
      "options": ["Epitome", "Epithet", "Epitaph", "Episode"],
      "answer": "Epitaph"
    },
    {
      "id": 552,
      "question": "নিচের কোনটি Noun ?",
      "options": ["Good", "City", "Upon"],
      "answer": "City"
    },
    {
      "id": 553,
      "question": "'Notation' has relevance to -",
      "options": ["Legal affairs", "Music", "Sports", "Insurance"],
      "answer": "Music"
    },
    {
      "id": 554,
      "question": "'Benefit' এর synonym হচ্ছে -",
      "options": ["Injury", "Drawback", "Favour", "Basement"],
      "answer": "Favour"
    },
    {
      "id": 555,
      "question": "Give the meaning of the word. The painter decided to 'Exhibit' his work in a gallery.",
      "options": ["Paint", "Show publicly", "Sell", "Present"],
      "answer": "Show publicly"
    },
    {
      "id": 556,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Eccentric' is -",
      "options": ["Angelic", "Erotic", "Normal", "Abnormal"],
      "answer": "Normal"
    },
    {
      "id": 557,
      "question": "The ministers arrived --- a decision last night.",
      "options": ["to", "at", "on", "by"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 558,
      "question": "What is the antonym 'Gentle'",
      "options": ["Harsh", "Modest", "Clever", "Rude"],
      "answer": "Rude"
    },
    {
      "id": 559,
      "question": "'Entreaty' শব্দটির অর্থ হচ্ছে -",
      "options": [
        "Diplomatic agreement",
        "Gentle Suggestion",
        "Full enjoyment",
        "Earnest request"
      ],
      "answer": "Earnest request"
    },
    {
      "id": 560,
      "question": "No man can ----- alone.",
      "options": ["live", "lives", "living", "lived"],
      "answer": "live"
    },
    {
      "id": 561,
      "question": "The meaning of the word 'Antiquated' is -",
      "options": ["Very old", "Ridiculous", "Out of date", "Absurd"],
      "answer": "Out of date"
    },
    {
      "id": 562,
      "question": "'Viable' means",
      "options": ["Possible", "That can be done", "Capable", "That will work"],
      "answer": "Capable"
    },
    {
      "id": 563,
      "question": "He apologize for his misdemeanor. A substitute for ' Misdemeanor' is -",
      "options": ["Malignity", "Mischievousness", "Misconduct", "Moodiness"],
      "answer": "Misconduct"
    },
    {
      "id": 564,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Vertical' ?",
      "options": ["Horizontal", "Erect", "Inclined", "Credit"],
      "answer": "Erect"
    },
    {
      "id": 565,
      "question": "The antonym for 'Snug' is -",
      "options": ["Tight", "New", "Loose", "Asleep"],
      "answer": "Loose"
    },
    {
      "id": 566,
      "question": "'Epitome' means -",
      "options": [
        "Very strange",
        "A perfect example of something",
        "Beauty",
        "Architecture"
      ],
      "answer": "A perfect example of something"
    },
    {
      "id": 567,
      "question": "A person who eats human flesh and animals that eats its own kind is called -",
      "options": ["Cannibal", "Flesh eater", "Meat eater", "Non-vegetarian"],
      "answer": "Cannibal"
    },
    {
      "id": 568,
      "question": "The opposite of 'commendable' is -",
      "options": [
        "Deserving",
        "Deplorable",
        "Regrettable",
        "Creditable",
        "Laudable"
      ],
      "answer": "Deplorable"
    },
    {
      "id": 569,
      "question": "'Tranquil' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Failure", "Negligence", "Frailty", "Energy"],
      "answer": "Frailty"
    },
    {
      "id": 570,
      "question": "Sheela is quick ---- understanding.",
      "options": ["at", "in", "for", "of"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 571,
      "question": "Choose the synoynm for 'Extempore'",
      "options": ["Planned", "Improvised", "Impromptu", "Immediate"],
      "answer": "Improvised"
    },
    {
      "id": 572,
      "question": "The word 'Contemporary' means",
      "options": ["Temporary", "Belonging to the same time", "Last", "Future"],
      "answer": "Belonging to the same time"
    },
    {
      "id": 573,
      "question": "Scanty' এর বিপরিতার্থক শব্দ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["Limited", "Unlimited", "Inflation", "Bounded"],
      "answer": "Limited"
    },
    {
      "id": 574,
      "question": "He is jealous ---- my fame. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["on", "for", "of", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 575,
      "question": "The noise level in Dhaka city has increased (exponentially).Here the bracket close word means -",
      "options": ["Amazingly", "Shockingly", "Steadily", "Rapidly"],
      "answer": "Rapidly"
    },
    {
      "id": 576,
      "question": "Pick appropriate preposition for the following sentence: Noureen will discuss the issue with Nasir ---- phone.",
      "options": ["in", "over", "by", "on"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 577,
      "question": "Pick the word that is synonymous with 'authoritarian'.",
      "options": ["Autocratic", "Senior", "Elderly", "Potential"],
      "answer": "Autocratic"
    },
    {
      "id": 578,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Serene'",
      "options": ["Severe", "Dark", "Calm", "Serious"],
      "answer": "Calm"
    },
    {
      "id": 579,
      "question": "'Subterfuge' means -",
      "options": ["Deception", "Smartness", "Very clever", "Frank"],
      "answer": "Deception"
    },
    {
      "id": 580,
      "question": "We went for a walk --- the rain.",
      "options": ["in", "during", "in spite of", "after"],
      "answer": "during"
    },
    {
      "id": 581,
      "question": "Choose the correct meaning of the phrase 'Cul-de-sac'",
      "options": ["Selection", "Dead end", "Error", "Bubble"],
      "answer": "Dead end"
    },
    {
      "id": 582,
      "question": "He has been ill --- Friday last.",
      "options": ["from", "on", "in", "since"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 583,
      "question": "He gave up --- football when he got married.",
      "options": ["of playing", "to play", "playing", "play"],
      "answer": "playing"
    },
    {
      "id": 584,
      "question": "Choose the synonym of the word 'Cop'",
      "options": ["Troops", "Scout", "Hit", "Police"],
      "answer": "Police"
    },
    {
      "id": 585,
      "question": "---- giving me books, he prepared notes for me.",
      "options": ["Along with", "Besides", "Beside", "Not only"],
      "answer": "Besides"
    },
    {
      "id": 586,
      "question": "A Machiavellian character is -",
      "options": [
        "An honest person",
        "A selfish person",
        "A courageous person",
        "A judicious person"
      ],
      "answer": "A selfish person"
    },
    {
      "id": 587,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Patriot' is -",
      "options": ["Treacherous person", "Tout", "Traitor", "Criminal"],
      "answer": "Traitor"
    },
    {
      "id": 588,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Famous' ?",
      "options": ["Opaque", "Illiterate", "Obscure", "Immature"],
      "answer": "Obscure"
    },
    {
      "id": 589,
      "question": "Tomorrow the President 'is going open a new hospital' this sentence missing word is -",
      "options": [
        "Is going open a new hospital",
        "Will going open a new hospital",
        "Is going to open a new hospital",
        "Will going to open a new hospital",
        "Will go to open a new hospital"
      ],
      "answer": "Is going to open a new hospital"
    },
    {
      "id": 590,
      "question": "'Vigour' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Failure", "Negligence", "Frailty", "Energy"],
      "answer": "Frailty"
    },
    {
      "id": 591,
      "question": "Which word is closest in meaning to ‘Franchise’?",
      "options": ["Privilege", "Utility", "Frankness", "Superficial"],
      "answer": "Privilege"
    },
    {
      "id": 592,
      "question": "He objects ---- having to go to so many parties.",
      "options": ["for", "against", "from", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 593,
      "question": "What is the correct synonym of 'Donated' ?",
      "options": ["Used", "Spent", "Contributed", "Channeled"],
      "answer": "Contributed"
    },
    {
      "id": 594,
      "question": "Debut",
      "options": [
        "Conclusion",
        "Contradiction",
        "Gracious response",
        "First appearance"
      ],
      "answer": "First appearance"
    },
    {
      "id": 595,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'De-facto'?",
      "options": ["Illegal", "Prodigal", "Defective", "In fact"],
      "answer": "In fact"
    },
    {
      "id": 596,
      "question": "Illicit - এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Fake", "Unlawful", "Legal", "Compatible"],
      "answer": "Unlawful"
    },
    {
      "id": 597,
      "question": "'Calm' এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Angry", "Quiet", "Agitated", "Irritated"],
      "answer": "Quiet"
    },
    {
      "id": 598,
      "question": "The lady is not amenable --- reason. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["on", "to", "for", "of"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 599,
      "question": "The opposite of the word 'diversity' is --",
      "options": [
        "similarity",
        "orginality",
        "longevity",
        "texture",
        "difficulty"
      ],
      "answer": "similarity"
    },
    {
      "id": 600,
      "question": "Philanthropist means -",
      "options": [
        "A person of chanty",
        "A person of wide view",
        "A hater of mankind",
        "A person with expert knowledge of postage"
      ],
      "answer": "A person of chanty"
    },
    {
      "id": 601,
      "question": "The virtuous (be) always happy. which one of the following is the correct verb or the word within bracket",
      "options": ["are", "is", "have been", "none of the above"],
      "answer": "are"
    },
    {
      "id": 602,
      "question": "He was absorbed --- deep thought. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["at", "in", "with", "on"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 603,
      "question": "A synonym for 'illusive' is -",
      "options": [
        "Not obvious",
        "Not coherent",
        "Not deceptive",
        "Not certain"
      ],
      "answer": "Not obvious"
    },
    {
      "id": 604,
      "question": "A man who is popular --- his neighbours is supposed to be a good man.",
      "options": ["to", "with", "among", "for"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 605,
      "question": "'Prima facie' means -",
      "options": [
        "Prime figure",
        "At first view",
        "Prime accused",
        "Prime minister"
      ],
      "answer": "At first view"
    },
    {
      "id": 606,
      "question": "\"Such claim needs to be tested empirically\" suggest that -",
      "options": [
        "The test should be based on",
        "The test should be based on idea",
        "The test should be based on experience",
        "The test should be based on calculation"
      ],
      "answer": "the test should be based on experience"
    },
    {
      "id": 607,
      "question": "The synonym of 'impromptu' is -",
      "options": ["Extempore", "Prepared", "Improper", "Direct"],
      "answer": "Extempore"
    },
    {
      "id": 608,
      "question": "Sumi is looking for an apartment ---- the park.",
      "options": ["at", "of", "to", "near"],
      "answer": "near"
    },
    {
      "id": 609,
      "question": "Utilize শব্দটির synonym হচ্ছে -",
      "options": ["Discard", "Employ", "Discharge", "Reject"],
      "answer": "Employ"
    },
    {
      "id": 610,
      "question": "A man who pays too much attention to his clothes and personal appearance --",
      "options": ["Licentious", "Dandy", "Duffer", "Snob"],
      "answer": "Dandy"
    },
    {
      "id": 611,
      "question": "The word 'Parsimony' means -",
      "options": ["Pathetic", "Miserable", "Miserliness", "Lavish"],
      "answer": "Miserliness"
    },
    {
      "id": 612,
      "question": "'Kinship' means",
      "options": ["A telephone box", "A bed", "Blood relation", "Strange"],
      "answer": "Blood relation"
    },
    {
      "id": 613,
      "question": "They thought that the plan would ---",
      "options": ["succeeded", "be succeeded", "succeed", "success"],
      "answer": "succeed"
    },
    {
      "id": 614,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Delete' ?",
      "options": ["Injure", "Delay", "Insert", "Trap"],
      "answer": "Insert"
    },
    {
      "id": 615,
      "question": "অবাক কাজ' এর ইংরেজী কি?",
      "options": [
        "What is strange",
        "The wonderful",
        "The beautiful work",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "The wonderful"
    },
    {
      "id": 616,
      "question": "He prevented me ---- going there.",
      "options": ["on", "from", "to", "of"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 617,
      "question": "what is the meaning of the expression 'bottom line'",
      "options": [
        "the final step",
        "the last line of a book",
        "the end of the road",
        "the essential point"
      ],
      "answer": "the essential point"
    },
    {
      "id": 618,
      "question": "I am fatigued ---- wide traveling.",
      "options": ["in", "by", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 619,
      "question": "The word 'hardly' means",
      "options": ["Always", "Almost never", "Seriously", "Regularly"],
      "answer": "Almost never"
    },
    {
      "id": 620,
      "question": "Cold এর antonym কি?",
      "options": ["Hard", "Hot", "Swift", "Strong"],
      "answer": "Hot"
    },
    {
      "id": 621,
      "question": "a synonym of 'extract'",
      "options": ["quote", "select", "insert", "collect"],
      "answer": "select"
    },
    {
      "id": 622,
      "question": "Rita sat on the corner of the table --- the door.",
      "options": ["of", "to", "near", "beside"],
      "answer": "beside"
    },
    {
      "id": 623,
      "question": "Select the alternative which best expresses the meaning of the given sentences: \"Not once has our neighbour invited us into his house\"",
      "options": [
        "Our neighbour has invited us into his house not once but many times",
        "Our neighbour has never invited us into his house",
        "Occasionally our neighbour has never invited us into his house",
        "Our neighbour has not always invited us into his house"
      ],
      "answer": "Our neighbour has never invited us into his house"
    },
    {
      "id": 624,
      "question": "Travellers ------ their reservation well in advance if they want to visit the st.martins island.",
      "options": [
        "had better to get",
        "had to better get",
        "had better get",
        "had better got"
      ],
      "answer": "had better get"
    },
    {
      "id": 625,
      "question": "We went --- a party --- rita's house on sunday.",
      "options": ["for , to", "to , at", "on , at", "to , to"],
      "answer": "to , at"
    },
    {
      "id": 626,
      "question": "To do away with' mens -",
      "options": ["to repeat", "to start", "to get rid of", "to drive off"],
      "answer": "to get rid of"
    },
    {
      "id": 627,
      "question": "I had (have) my meal before you came.",
      "options": ["had", "have", "been", "have been"],
      "answer": "had"
    },
    {
      "id": 628,
      "question": "There are people who can't help ---- when they see someone slip on a banana skin.",
      "options": ["crying", "laughing", "shouting", "anything"],
      "answer": "laughing"
    },
    {
      "id": 629,
      "question": "Ordinance এর বাংলা অর্থ -",
      "options": ["সমরাস্ত্র", "অধ্যাদেশ", "আদেশ", "বিশেষ ক্ষমতাবলে নির্দেশ"],
      "answer": "অধ্যাদেশ"
    },
    {
      "id": 630,
      "question": "'Proscribe' means -",
      "options": ["Advise", "Seize", "Take into custody", "Prohibit"],
      "answer": "Prohibit"
    },
    {
      "id": 631,
      "question": "'Expound' is similar to --",
      "options": ["confound", "perplex", "explain", "obscure"],
      "answer": "explain"
    },
    {
      "id": 632,
      "question": "'Barter' is similar to --",
      "options": ["transient", "proxy", "relevant", "useful", "ex]hange"],
      "answer": "exchange"
    },
    {
      "id": 633,
      "question": "The word 'Plight' means -",
      "options": [
        "An unpleasant condition",
        "An unusual condition",
        "An undesirable condition",
        "An unstable condition"
      ],
      "answer": "An unpleasant condition"
    },
    {
      "id": 634,
      "question": "I should appreciate if you complete this work --- thursday.",
      "options": ["till", "until", "upto", "by"],
      "answer": "by"
    },
    {
      "id": 635,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'apostate' ?",
      "options": ["Loyalist", "Cancellation", "Poverty", "Believe"],
      "answer": "Loyalist"
    },
    {
      "id": 636,
      "question": "Complete the sentence : he talks as if -----?",
      "options": ["he was mad", "he were mad", "he had been mad", "he is mad"],
      "answer": "he were mad"
    },
    {
      "id": 637,
      "question": "I prefer working ---- a deadline.",
      "options": ["to", "for", "on", "with"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 638,
      "question": "Dessert is -",
      "options": [
        "Course of fruits etc. at the end of a meal",
        "Barren land",
        "Go away from",
        "To be rewarded"
      ],
      "answer": "Course of fruits etc. at the end of a meal"
    },
    {
      "id": 639,
      "question": "What is the antonym of the word 'narrow' ?",
      "options": ["Deep", "Broad", "Shallow", "Rough"],
      "answer": "Droad"
    },
    {
      "id": 640,
      "question": "'Percel' means -",
      "options": ["Quarrel", "Piece of land", "Postage", "Unobstructed view"],
      "answer": "Piece of land"
    },
    {
      "id": 641,
      "question": "The antonym of 'hazardous' is -",
      "options": ["Certain", "Clear", "Safe", "Dangerous"],
      "answer": "Safe"
    },
    {
      "id": 642,
      "question": "Fill in the blank with right option: i am looking forward --- you.",
      "options": ["to seeing", "seeing", "to see", "to have seen"],
      "answer": "to seeing"
    },
    {
      "id": 643,
      "question": "Which of the following set contain the correct meaning ?",
      "options": [
        "Antipathy : Strong dislike",
        "Bequeath : Determined to go",
        "Collide : Indifferent",
        "Devolve : Without"
      ],
      "answer": "Antipathy : Strong dislike"
    },
    {
      "id": 644,
      "question": "Hell শব্দের অর্থ",
      "options": ["ঊর্ধ্ব", "স্বর্গ", "অধঃ", "নরক"],
      "answer": "নরক"
    },
    {
      "id": 645,
      "question": "You are looking smart --- this dress.",
      "options": ["after", "in", "with", "of"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 646,
      "question": "It is who -- to blame বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে-",
      "options": ["was", "is", "are", "has"],
      "answer": "are"
    },
    {
      "id": 647,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'Sequence'?",
      "options": ["To follow", "Round up", "Withdraw", "Question closely"],
      "answer": "To follow"
    },
    {
      "id": 648,
      "question": "the correct synonym of the word 'astute' is",
      "options": ["autistic", "shrewd", "economic", "acute"],
      "answer": "shrewd"
    },
    {
      "id": 649,
      "question": "A synonym for 'Appraise' is",
      "options": [
        "Explain",
        "Perceive",
        "Elaborate",
        "Criticize",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "None of these"
    },
    {
      "id": 650,
      "question": "The synonym of 'desultory' is -",
      "options": [
        "Organized",
        "Disorganized",
        "Drive",
        "Methodical",
        "Romantic"
      ],
      "answer": "Disorganized"
    },
    {
      "id": 651,
      "question": "'Enunciate' is most nearly similar in meaning to --",
      "options": ["pray", "request", "deliver", "mumble"],
      "answer": "mumble"
    },
    {
      "id": 652,
      "question": "He is devoid --- common sense.",
      "options": ["of", "from", "introduction", "at"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 653,
      "question": "\"exact\" is the antonym of",
      "options": ["nearly", "approximate", "closely", "so so"],
      "answer": "approximate"
    },
    {
      "id": 654,
      "question": "'edifice' means",
      "options": [
        "huge quantity",
        "serious problem",
        "a large imposing building",
        "superficial"
      ],
      "answer": "a large imposing building"
    },
    {
      "id": 655,
      "question": "The word 'homogeneous' means -",
      "options": [
        "Of the same kind",
        "Of the same place",
        "Of the same race",
        "Of the same density"
      ],
      "answer": "of the same kind"
    },
    {
      "id": 656,
      "question": "Travellers ------ their reservation well in advance if they want to fly during the eid holidays.",
      "options": [
        "had better to get",
        "had to get better",
        "had better get",
        "had better got"
      ],
      "answer": "had better get"
    },
    {
      "id": 657,
      "question": "The government gave --- the demands of the people.",
      "options": ["in to", "into", "to", "over to"],
      "answer": "in to"
    },
    {
      "id": 658,
      "question": "Which of the following word is the correct synonym of 'libel' ?",
      "options": ["Convincing", "Annihilate", "Enervated", "Misrepresentation"],
      "answer": "Misrepresentation"
    },
    {
      "id": 659,
      "question": "The word 'Decade' means -",
      "options": [
        "Rotten objects",
        "Decaying old age",
        "A group of ten people",
        "A period of ten years"
      ],
      "answer": "A period of ten years"
    },
    {
      "id": 660,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Absorbed'",
      "options": ["Fatigued", "Disturbed", "Engrossed", "Successful"],
      "answer": "Engrossed"
    },
    {
      "id": 661,
      "question": "Who among the following writers is not a nobel laureate?",
      "options": ["T.S.Eliot", "Toni Morrison", "Grahame Greene", "William"],
      "answer": "Grahame Greene"
    },
    {
      "id": 662,
      "question": "in space , the primary necessities ---- survival are air, food and water.",
      "options": ["of", "for", "about", "in"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 663,
      "question": "brittle এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["fragile", "soft", "strong", "hard"],
      "answer": "fragile"
    },
    {
      "id": 664,
      "question": "'quarrel' শব্দটির synonym হচ্ছে",
      "options": ["agreement", "reconciliation", "peace", "dispute"],
      "answer": "dispute"
    },
    {
      "id": 665,
      "question": "Find out the plural number ---",
      "options": ["Mice", "Goose", "Woman", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Mice"
    },
    {
      "id": 666,
      "question": "'Neglect' এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["Care", "Attention", "Carelessness", "Watchfulness"],
      "answer": "Carelessness"
    },
    {
      "id": 667,
      "question": "His wife reminded him ----?",
      "options": [
        "of his appointment",
        "to go his appointment",
        "to his appointment",
        "his appointment"
      ],
      "answer": "of his appointment"
    },
    {
      "id": 668,
      "question": "'You should drive the car at a speed compatible ---- safety' বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে --",
      "options": ["for", "towards", "at", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 669,
      "question": "The word calamity means -",
      "options": ["competent", "casual", "catastrophe", "celebrated"],
      "answer": "catastrophe"
    },
    {
      "id": 670,
      "question": "Fill the blank with correct word: The women was seen --- the ring in her bag.",
      "options": ["Putting", "Put in", "Put on", "wWs putting"],
      "answer": "Putting"
    },
    {
      "id": 671,
      "question": "As a sinner i must go ----- the whole trial ---- suffering.",
      "options": ["through , of", "on , of", "by , in", "with , at"],
      "answer": "through , of"
    },
    {
      "id": 672,
      "question": "Synonym for 'Narcissism'",
      "options": ["Notable", "Self love", "Dignity", "Admiration for beauty"],
      "answer": "Self love"
    },
    {
      "id": 673,
      "question": "Many years have passed since i ---- my friend.",
      "options": ["had met", "met", "meet", "have been met"],
      "answer": "met"
    },
    {
      "id": 674,
      "question": "Shallow is opposite to -",
      "options": ["arbitrary", "painstaking", "profound", "restive"],
      "answer": "profound"
    },
    {
      "id": 675,
      "question": "কোনটি 'Vacant' শব্দের সমার্থক শব্দ ?",
      "options": ["Blank", "Engaged", "Busy", "Employed"],
      "answer": "Blank"
    },
    {
      "id": 676,
      "question": "Courteous and attentive to women means -",
      "options": [
        "Querulous",
        "Chivalrous",
        "Supercilious",
        "Dolorous",
        "Ob]equious"
      ],
      "answer": "Chivalrous"
    },
    {
      "id": 677,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'abstain'",
      "options": ["Continue", "Good", "Paused", "Last"],
      "answer": "Paused"
    },
    {
      "id": 678,
      "question": "'Flora' means --",
      "options": [
        "Elaborate decoration with flowers",
        "All the flowers of an area",
        "A garland of flowers",
        "All the plants of an area"
      ],
      "answer": "All the plants of an area"
    },
    {
      "id": 679,
      "question": "Fill in the gap with proper word: i saw him ----",
      "options": ["go", "went", "going", "gone"],
      "answer": "going"
    },
    {
      "id": 680,
      "question": "The sentence\"Who would have thought Shylock was so unkind\" expresses",
      "options": ["Hyperbole", "Interrogation", "Command", "Wonder"],
      "answer": "Wonder"
    },
    {
      "id": 681,
      "question": "A cure for all diseases --",
      "options": ["Exorcism", "Incantation", "Panacea", "Antibiotic"],
      "answer": "Panacea"
    },
    {
      "id": 682,
      "question": "Identify the sentence with appropriate preposition -----",
      "options": [
        "\"You need not look on it\",said delia.",
        "I don't believe in learning luxurious life",
        "It is 7 o'clock on my watch",
        "The patient died from malaria"
      ],
      "answer": "I don't believe in learning luxurious life"
    },
    {
      "id": 683,
      "question": "An Ordinance is -",
      "options": ["A book", "A law", "A newspaper", "A manuscript"],
      "answer": "A law"
    },
    {
      "id": 684,
      "question": "A phlegmatic person is someone who --",
      "options": [
        "Quarrels with everybody",
        "Helps poor people",
        "Remains calm and does not get excited easily",
        "Does not believe in god"
      ],
      "answer": "Remains calm and does not get excited easily"
    },
    {
      "id": 685,
      "question": "A cardologist treats patients with -------- problems.",
      "options": ["Heart", "Kidney", "Urine", "Stomach"],
      "answer": "Heart"
    },
    {
      "id": 686,
      "question": "Synonym of the word 'sequel' --",
      "options": ["Continuance", "Prologue", "Preamble", "Prelude"],
      "answer": "Continuance"
    },
    {
      "id": 687,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Remember' is -",
      "options": ["Call up", "Memory", "Forget", "Recollect"],
      "answer": "Recollect"
    },
    {
      "id": 688,
      "question": "'Break' এর সমার্থক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Unit", "Smash", "Join", "Assemble"],
      "answer": "Smash"
    },
    {
      "id": 689,
      "question": "--- his earlier study, the professor's new study indicates a general warning trend in global weather.",
      "options": [
        "In contrast of",
        "In contrast to",
        "In contrast by",
        "In contrast as"
      ],
      "answer": "in contrast to"
    },
    {
      "id": 690,
      "question": "Who will account ---- the loss ?",
      "options": ["at", "of", "for", "about"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 691,
      "question": "The children were entrusted --- the care of their uncle",
      "options": ["with", "for", "to", "at"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 692,
      "question": "Which is the correct sentence?",
      "options": [
        "I wish i was in your shoes",
        "I wish i were in your shoes",
        "I wish i got into your shoes",
        "I wish i get into your shoes"
      ],
      "answer": "I wish i were in your shoes"
    },
    {
      "id": 693,
      "question": "I stretched for tissue but the box of tissues -- nearly empty.",
      "options": ["was", "were", "has", "have", "None of these"],
      "answer": "was"
    },
    {
      "id": 694,
      "question": "The aggrieved parties 'acceded' to the proposal.(synonym)",
      "options": ["Added to", "Reduced", "Awaited", "Proposed", "De]lined"],
      "answer": "Added to"
    },
    {
      "id": 695,
      "question": "Choose the correct meaning of the word 'Likely'",
      "options": ["Possibly", "Very much liked", "Similarly", "Nearly"],
      "answer": "Possibly"
    },
    {
      "id": 696,
      "question": "'Spacious' is the antonym of -",
      "options": ["typical", "narrow", "golden", "genuine", "none of these"],
      "answer": "narrow"
    },
    {
      "id": 697,
      "question": "Which one means 'unlimited power'?",
      "options": ["Omnipresent", "Omniscient", "Omnipotent", "Omnibus"],
      "answer": "Omnipotent"
    },
    {
      "id": 698,
      "question": "Ring master is a person in charge of --",
      "options": [
        "A bus counter",
        "A circus performance",
        "A cinema hall",
        "A dramatic performance"
      ],
      "answer": "A circus performance"
    },
    {
      "id": 699,
      "question": "The meaning of 'conjecture' is related to --",
      "options": ["continuity", "doubtfully", "deeply", "mostly", "simply"],
      "answer": "doubtfully"
    },
    {
      "id": 700,
      "question": "'Mercenary' is the synonym of --",
      "options": ["Hired", "Voluntary", "Venal", "Mean"],
      "answer": "Hired"
    },
    {
      "id": 701,
      "question": "Fill in the blank. he ran 10 kilometers --- stopping.",
      "options": ["often", "seldom", "without", "continuously"],
      "answer": "without"
    },
    {
      "id": 702,
      "question": "Meaning of the word 'Aboriginal' --",
      "options": ["hateful", "primitive", "modern", "amuring", "attractive"],
      "answer": "primitive"
    },
    {
      "id": 703,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'Active'?",
      "options": ["Able", "Up and doing", "Energetic", "Forceful"],
      "answer": "Up and doing"
    },
    {
      "id": 704,
      "question": "'Millennium' is a period of --",
      "options": ["100 years", "500 years", "1000 years", "2500 years"],
      "answer": "1000 years"
    },
    {
      "id": 705,
      "question": "My mother had me ---- milk every",
      "options": ["to drinking", "drinking", "drink", "drank"],
      "answer": "drink"
    },
    {
      "id": 706,
      "question": "instead of 'confirm' we can say --",
      "options": ["Bear out", "Bear on", "Bear to", "Bear off"],
      "answer": "Bear out"
    },
    {
      "id": 707,
      "question": "Will you mind --- the accounts one more time?",
      "options": ["checking", "to check", "checked", "check"],
      "answer": "checking"
    },
    {
      "id": 708,
      "question": "A synonym of 'Faithful' is --",
      "options": ["Loyal", "Deceitful", "Extravagant", "Hateful"],
      "answer": "Loyal"
    },
    {
      "id": 709,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'equivocation' is --",
      "options": ["Fairness", "Evasion", "Imprecation", "Equality"],
      "answer": "Evasion"
    },
    {
      "id": 710,
      "question": "I am not bad --- tennis.",
      "options": ["in", "at", "about", "with"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 711,
      "question": "'Sloth' is the antonym of --",
      "options": ["Activity", "Idleness", "Laziness", "Indolence"],
      "answer": "Activity"
    },
    {
      "id": 712,
      "question": "Query শব্দটির অর্থ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["solution", "question", "dissolved", "ratify"],
      "answer": "question"
    },
    {
      "id": 713,
      "question": "Gullible' means",
      "options": [
        "Foolish",
        "Willing to believe anything or anyone",
        "Simple",
        "Easily deceived"
      ],
      "answer": "Easily deceived"
    },
    {
      "id": 714,
      "question": "We need two hundred dollars --- this to pay for everything.",
      "options": ["as well", "also", "beside", "besides"],
      "answer": "besides"
    },
    {
      "id": 715,
      "question": "I finally killed the fly ---- a rolled up newspaper.",
      "options": ["by", "with", "through", "from"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 716,
      "question": "Choose the one that best expresses the meaning of the given word: IMPROVEMENT",
      "options": ["Promotion", "Advancement", "Betterment", "Preference"],
      "answer": "Betterment"
    },
    {
      "id": 717,
      "question": "Which word is different from the other three?",
      "options": ["media", "war", "newspaper", "radio"],
      "answer": "war"
    },
    {
      "id": 718,
      "question": "যে ভাষা থেকে Education শব্দটির উৎপত্তি হয়েছে",
      "options": ["ইংরেজী", "ফরাসী", "জার্মান", "লাতিন"],
      "answer": "লাতিন"
    },
    {
      "id": 719,
      "question": "A sound which cannot be heard -- ",
      "options": ["Audible", "Inaudible", "Obsolete", "Whisper"],
      "answer": "Inaudible"
    },
    {
      "id": 720,
      "question": "The teacher failed to make the students --- to him.",
      "options": ["to listen", "listening", "listened", "listen"],
      "answer": "listen"
    },
    {
      "id": 721,
      "question": "What kind of man is quite the opposite type of 'supercilious' ?",
      "options": ["Affable", "Haughty", "Disdainful", "Wicked"],
      "answer": "Affable"
    },
    {
      "id": 722,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'competent' ?",
      "options": ["Circumspect", "Discrete", "Capable", "Prudent"],
      "answer": "Capable"
    },
    {
      "id": 723,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'incredible' ?",
      "options": ["Unbelievable", "Unthinkable", "Unlikely", "Unthinking"],
      "answer": "Unbelievable"
    },
    {
      "id": 724,
      "question": "The verb 'succumb' means -",
      "options": ["achieve", "submit", "wind", "conquer"],
      "answer": "submit"
    },
    {
      "id": 725,
      "question": "'Scarcity' is opposite to --",
      "options": ["abundance", "mediocre", "remote", "little", "none of these"],
      "answer": "abundance"
    },
    {
      "id": 726,
      "question": "He fantasized ---- winning the lottery.",
      "options": ["with", "from", "after", "about"],
      "answer": "about"
    },
    {
      "id": 727,
      "question": "the word 'ecological' is related to --",
      "options": ["Atmosphere", "Pollution", "Environment", "Demography"],
      "answer": "Environment"
    },
    {
      "id": 728,
      "question": "An 'erratic' person is one who is",
      "options": ["Pleasant", "Honest", "Unreliable", "Rational"],
      "answer": "Unreliable"
    },
    {
      "id": 729,
      "question": "choose the one that best expresses the meaning of the given word: improvement",
      "options": ["promotion", "advancement", "betterment", "preference"],
      "answer": "betterment"
    },
    {
      "id": 730,
      "question": "'Heptagone' means -",
      "options": ["Five sides", "Triangangle", "Seven sides", "Straight"],
      "answer": "Seven sides"
    },
    {
      "id": 731,
      "question": "Choose the word opposite in meaning to the given word: HATE",
      "options": ["Admire", "Abhor", "Concern", "Loathe"],
      "answer": "Admire"
    },
    {
      "id": 732,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Indigenious'",
      "options": ["Locale", "Distant", "Foreign", "Native"],
      "answer": "Native"
    },
    {
      "id": 733,
      "question": "Choose the appropriate word or words to complete the sentence below: rafique saw --- digging in his garden.",
      "options": ["Mr. Ali was", "That Mr. Ali", "Mr. Ali is", "Mr. Ali"],
      "answer": "Mr. Ali"
    },
    {
      "id": 734,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'encounter' is --",
      "options": ["Concord", "Harmony", "Battle", "Part"],
      "answer": "Battle"
    },
    {
      "id": 735,
      "question": "I am not good ---- translation.",
      "options": ["in", "about", "with", "at"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 736,
      "question": "We should not yield ---- any pressure.",
      "options": ["to", "for", "from", "of"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 737,
      "question": "Choose the world that is opposite in meaning to the word 'irreversible' ?",
      "options": [
        "temporary",
        "occasional",
        "changeable",
        "permanent",
        "irrevocable"
      ],
      "answer": "changeable"
    },
    {
      "id": 738,
      "question": "The antonym for the word 'Resemblance' is --",
      "options": ["Identity", "Dimilarity", "Difference", "Dissembling"],
      "answer": "Difference"
    },
    {
      "id": 739,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Harbinger' is --",
      "options": ["Leader", "Educator", "Messenger", "Wastrel"],
      "answer": "Wastrel"
    },
    {
      "id": 740,
      "question": "You should avail --- yourself this opportunity.",
      "options": ["of", "to", "in", "from", "none of these"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 741,
      "question": "Had i been reach i (help) her.choose the correct form of verb --",
      "options": [
        "would help",
        "will help",
        "would have helped",
        "will have helped"
      ],
      "answer": "would have helped"
    },
    {
      "id": 742,
      "question": "A synonym of 'functional' is --",
      "options": ["Practical", "Passive", "Peculiar", "Pedantic"],
      "answer": "Practical"
    },
    {
      "id": 743,
      "question": "The teacher asked the boys to stop ---. Which of the following is the correct verb form in the blank above?",
      "options": ["Writing", "To write", "Write", "for writing"],
      "answer": "Writing"
    },
    {
      "id": 744,
      "question": "Full শব্দটির synonym হচ্ছে -",
      "options": ["Filled", "Fulfilment", "Fill", "Full"],
      "answer": "Full"
    },
    {
      "id": 745,
      "question": "'Populour' এর বাংলা অর্থ -",
      "options": ["জনসাধারন", "জনপ্রিয়", "জনবহুল", "জনসংখ্যা"],
      "answer": "জনসাধারন"
    },
    {
      "id": 746,
      "question": "The word 'Exaggerated' is closet in meaning to --",
      "options": ["Modest", "Concise", "More than normal", "New"],
      "answer": "More than normal"
    },
    {
      "id": 747,
      "question": "Which of the following is a correct proverb ?",
      "options": [
        "Fools rush in where an angels fear to tread",
        "Fools rush in where an angel fears to tread",
        "A fool rushes in where an angel fears to tread",
        "Fools rush in where an angel fear to tread"
      ],
      "answer": "Fools rush in where an angels fear to tread"
    },
    {
      "id": 748,
      "question": "'Everything hinges --- what happens next' বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["by", "upon", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "upon"
    },
    {
      "id": 749,
      "question": "What is the closest word to the following word 'Degradation' ?",
      "options": ["Dishonor", "Embarrassment", "Bewilderment", "Anger"],
      "answer": "Dishonor"
    },
    {
      "id": 750,
      "question": "What is the correct preposition in the sentence ' the case is ----- trail'.",
      "options": ["on", "at", "under", "for"],
      "answer": "under"
    },
    {
      "id": 751,
      "question": "I get up before ----- sunrise .",
      "options": ["a", "an", "the", "at"],
      "answer": "the"
    },
    {
      "id": 752,
      "question": "The meaning of the word 'Comprehension' is --",
      "options": [
        "Application",
        "Apprehension",
        "Compounding",
        "Understanding"
      ],
      "answer": "Understanding"
    },
    {
      "id": 753,
      "question": "Early rising is coducive --- health.",
      "options": ["for", "of", "to", "on"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 754,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Decorous'?",
      "options": ["Ugly", "Proper", "Fatty", "Strange"],
      "answer": "Proper"
    },
    {
      "id": 755,
      "question": "I prevailed ---- my friend to lend me tk.5000.",
      "options": ["over", "with", "upon", "against"],
      "answer": "upon"
    },
    {
      "id": 756,
      "question": "The lady had a 'puzzled' look on her face.",
      "options": [
        "Beautiful",
        "Good",
        "Happy",
        "Unable to understand",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Unable to understand"
    },
    {
      "id": 757,
      "question": "Choose the best answer.",
      "options": [
        "He discourages me to borrows",
        "He discourages me from borrowing",
        "He discourages from me borrowing",
        "He discourages me to borrowing"
      ],
      "answer": "He discourages me from borrowing"
    },
    {
      "id": 758,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym of the word 'Glowing' ?",
      "options": ["Without show", "Dull", "Without glittter", "Boring"],
      "answer": "Dull"
    },
    {
      "id": 759,
      "question": "He could not 'deny' that.",
      "options": ["Decide", "Accept", "Confusion", "Refuse", "None of these"],
      "answer": "Accept"
    },
    {
      "id": 760,
      "question": "To express a past habit or state which one will be the correct expression?",
      "options": [
        "I came here when i was child",
        "I had come here when i was a child",
        "I used to come here when i was a child",
        "I would come here when i was a child"
      ],
      "answer": "I used to come here when i was a child"
    },
    {
      "id": 761,
      "question": "There is no royal road ---- learning.",
      "options": ["to", "by", "for", "from"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 762,
      "question": "Subconscious' শব্দটির বাংলা পরিভাষিক শব্দ হল -",
      "options": ["অধচেতন", "অবচেতন", "চেতনাহীন", "চেতনাপ্রবাহ"],
      "answer": "অবচেতন"
    },
    {
      "id": 763,
      "question": "The word 'Altercation' means -",
      "options": ["Adjustment", "Replace", "Quarrel", "Repairing"],
      "answer": "Quarrel"
    },
    {
      "id": 764,
      "question": "Select the right word: it is high time you ---- up smoking.",
      "options": ["give", "gave", "have given", "will give"],
      "answer": "gave"
    },
    {
      "id": 765,
      "question": "Where has this letter come --?",
      "options": ["to", "on", "from", "for"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 766,
      "question": "'সততা সর্বোৎকৃষ্ট পন্থা' - কোনটির অনুবাদ ?",
      "options": [
        "Honesty is the best virtue",
        "Honesty is the better way",
        "Honesty is a good way",
        "Honesty is the best policy"
      ],
      "answer": "Honesty is the best policy"
    },
    {
      "id": 767,
      "question": "Without health there is no happiness. এখানে happiness শব্দটি কোন প্রকারের noun?",
      "options": ["Proper", "Common", "Collective", "Abstract"],
      "answer": "Abstract"
    },
    {
      "id": 768,
      "question": "The word 'euphemism' means ---?",
      "options": [
        "Stating one thing like another",
        "Description of disagreeable thing by an agreeable name",
        "Contrast of words is made in the same sentence",
        "A statement is made emphatic by over statement"
      ],
      "answer": "Description of disagreeable thing by an agreeable name"
    },
    {
      "id": 769,
      "question": "The synonym of 'symphony' is --",
      "options": ["Singer", "Composer", "Consonance", "Harmony of sound"],
      "answer": "Harmony of sound"
    },
    {
      "id": 770,
      "question": "\"He has assured me ---- safety.\"",
      "options": ["with", "at", "for", "of"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 771,
      "question": "The money we asked ---- was not forthcoming.",
      "options": ["for", "after", "about", "around"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 772,
      "question": "Find the synonym of the word 'Myopic'",
      "options": [
        "Evenhanded",
        "Unprejudiced",
        "Tolerant",
        "Short-sighted",
        "Open-minded"
      ],
      "answer": "Short-sighted"
    },
    {
      "id": 773,
      "question": "Honesty is indispensible ---- success.",
      "options": ["at", "for", "to", "on"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 774,
      "question": "Choose the word opposite in meaning to the given word: \"Repeal\"",
      "options": ["Abolish", "Enact", "Annul", "Nullify"],
      "answer": "Enact"
    },
    {
      "id": 775,
      "question": "Choose the correct sentence.",
      "options": [
        "The train is running in time",
        "The train is running on time",
        "The train is running with time",
        "The train is running to time"
      ],
      "answer": "The train is running on time"
    },
    {
      "id": 776,
      "question": "'Daunt' is the synonym of --",
      "options": ["Intimidate", "Overwhelm", "Dared", "Show off"],
      "answer": "Intimidate"
    },
    {
      "id": 777,
      "question": "People ----- aeroplanes now a days.",
      "options": [
        "used to see",
        "were used to seeing",
        "used to seeing",
        "are used to seeing",
        "seeing"
      ],
      "answer": "are used to seeing"
    },
    {
      "id": 778,
      "question": "Complete the following sentence lots of people are allergic ---- prawn.",
      "options": ["from", "with", "in", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 779,
      "question": "''Ad valorem'' means -",
      "options": ["Invaluable", "Valuable", "According to valued", "Valueless"],
      "answer": "According to valued"
    },
    {
      "id": 780,
      "question": "A person unable to pay his debts --",
      "options": ["Poor", "Solvent", "Miser", "Insolvent"],
      "answer": "Insolvent"
    },
    {
      "id": 781,
      "question": "The meaning of 'magnanimity' is --",
      "options": ["Meanness", "Generosity", "Selfishness", "Splendid"],
      "answer": "Generosity"
    },
    {
      "id": 782,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'hypothetical' is --",
      "options": ["Suspicious", "Philosophical", "Assumed", "Complete"],
      "answer": "Assumed"
    },
    {
      "id": 783,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'limpid' ?",
      "options": ["Watery", "Bright", "Muddy", "Transparent"],
      "answer": "Muddy"
    },
    {
      "id": 784,
      "question": "Stay where you are until help --",
      "options": ["arrives", "arrived", "to arrive", "arriving"],
      "answer": "arrives"
    },
    {
      "id": 785,
      "question": "The synonym of 'abstain' is --",
      "options": ["tardy", "longing", "refrain", "impossible", "tiny"],
      "answer": "refrain"
    },
    {
      "id": 786,
      "question": "immune is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "toxic",
        "having little energy",
        "having no resistance",
        "virulent"
      ],
      "answer": "having no resistance"
    },
    {
      "id": 787,
      "question": "He is afflicted --- gout. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["to", "with", "of", "on"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 788,
      "question": "My opinion coincided ---- you. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["at", "against", "with", "for"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 789,
      "question": "There is the Jamuna bridge ----- the river of jamuna.",
      "options": ["on", "above", "over", "upon"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 790,
      "question": "The word 'Mandatory' means -",
      "options": ["Optional", "Obligatory", "Subsidiary", "Done by man"],
      "answer": "Obligatory"
    },
    {
      "id": 791,
      "question": "to 'brog' to -",
      "options": [
        "boast",
        "pull or carry a heavy load",
        "push into place",
        "barks like a dog"
      ],
      "answer": "boast"
    },
    {
      "id": 792,
      "question": "What is the opposite of 'cowardice'",
      "options": ["Speed", "Sun", "Bravery", "Speech"],
      "answer": "Bravery"
    },
    {
      "id": 793,
      "question": "Maiden speech 'means",
      "options": [
        "late speech",
        "early speech",
        "final speech",
        "first speech"
      ],
      "answer": "first speech"
    },
    {
      "id": 794,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Indignant' --",
      "options": ["Anargy", "Improper", "Unskilled", "Note distinct"],
      "answer": "Anargy"
    },
    {
      "id": 795,
      "question": "Broad শব্দটি Abstract form হবে ?",
      "options": ["Breadth", "Broadness", "Broder", "Bradship"],
      "answer": "Broadness"
    },
    {
      "id": 796,
      "question": "I am ashamed --- his conduct.",
      "options": ["to", "of", "on", "for"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 797,
      "question": "It was our policy to deal with the problems as they --",
      "options": ["arose", "rose", "raised", "roused"],
      "answer": "arose"
    },
    {
      "id": 798,
      "question": "'Prior to' means -",
      "options": ["after", "before", "immediately", "during the period of"],
      "answer": "before"
    },
    {
      "id": 799,
      "question": "'Elucidate' is the synonym of -",
      "options": ["confuse", "perplex", "extreme", "expound", "none of them"],
      "answer": "expound"
    },
    {
      "id": 800,
      "question": "'Linguist' means",
      "options": ["Absconder", "Swindler", "Polyglot", "Knowledgeable"],
      "answer": "Polyglot"
    },
    {
      "id": 801,
      "question": "Microbiology - এর পরিভাষা নিচের কোনটি ?",
      "options": [
        "অনুপ্রাণ বিজ্ঞান",
        "অনুজীব বিজ্ঞান",
        "জীবানু বিজ্ঞান",
        "কোনটিই নয়"
      ],
      "answer": "অনুজীব বিজ্ঞান"
    },
    {
      "id": 802,
      "question": "The word 'liberty'means",
      "options": ["freedom", "independence", "liberal", "lawlessness"],
      "answer": "freedom"
    },
    {
      "id": 803,
      "question": "You must adhere ---- your principal. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["in", "on", "at", "to"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 804,
      "question": "The disgusted man grumbled --- his fate.",
      "options": ["on", "to", "against", "at"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 805,
      "question": "A suitable antonym for 'Contentions' is -",
      "options": ["Amenable", "Inactive", "Dispassionate", "Severe"],
      "answer": "Amenable"
    },
    {
      "id": 806,
      "question": "A modest man does not boast --- his merit.",
      "options": ["of", "on", "for", "with"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 807,
      "question": "My brother has no appetite --- food.",
      "options": ["at", "for", "to", "in"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 808,
      "question": "Fill in the blanks. I shall do it ---- pleasure.",
      "options": ["in", "at", "into", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 809,
      "question": "'Subjudice' means",
      "options": ["অনাস্থা", "বিচারকের বেঞ্চ", "বিশেষ আদালত", "বিচারাধীন"],
      "answer": "বিচারাধীন"
    },
    {
      "id": 810,
      "question": "English is --- in many countries.",
      "options": ["spoken", "spoke", "speaking", "speaks"],
      "answer": "spoken"
    },
    {
      "id": 811,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Latent' is -",
      "options": ["Unclear", "Dormant", "Obscured", "Obvious"],
      "answer": "Dormant"
    },
    {
      "id": 812,
      "question": "Choose the correct meaning of the word 'Viable' ?",
      "options": ["possible", "that can be done", "capable", "that will work"],
      "answer": "capable"
    },
    {
      "id": 813,
      "question": "How did you get an appointment --- Dr. Howard?",
      "options": ["by", "with", "at", "to"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 814,
      "question": "Why are you so angry ---- ?",
      "options": ["about", "at", "with", "for"],
      "answer": "for"
    },
    {
      "id": 815,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'Authentic' is -",
      "options": ["Correct", "Genuine", "Real", "Exact", "True"],
      "answer": "Genuine"
    },
    {
      "id": 816,
      "question": "A suitable antonym for 'Demise' is -",
      "options": ["Integrity", "Irritative", "Birth", "Excess"],
      "answer": "Birth"
    },
    {
      "id": 817,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Refute' is -",
      "options": ["Disprove", "Prompt", "Laud", "Adept"],
      "answer": "Disprove"
    },
    {
      "id": 818,
      "question": "Select the correct preposition. Happiness consists ---- contenment.",
      "options": ["in", "of", "with", "for"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 819,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Aroma' is -",
      "options": ["Food", "Fruits", "Colorless", "Fragrance"],
      "answer": "Fragrance"
    },
    {
      "id": 820,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Attraction' ?",
      "options": ["Lure", "Charm", "Repulsive", "Attractiveness"],
      "answer": "Repulsive"
    },
    {
      "id": 821,
      "question": "Complete the sentence with the correct verb from : Neela --- her hand when she was cooking dinner.",
      "options": ["is burning", "burnt", "will burn", "was burning"],
      "answer": "burnt"
    },
    {
      "id": 822,
      "question": "The synonym for 'Mouth watering' is -",
      "options": ["Hot", "Wet", "Sour", "Delicious"],
      "answer": "Delicious"
    },
    {
      "id": 823,
      "question": "She was blessed --- a son. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["by", "for", "in", "with"],
      "answer": "with"
    },
    {
      "id": 824,
      "question": "'Carnal' is nearly opposite to -",
      "options": ["Fleshy", "Sensual", "Animal", "Virtuous"],
      "answer": "Virtuous"
    },
    {
      "id": 825,
      "question": "An honest man has on distrust ---- anyone. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["on", "with", "for", "of"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 826,
      "question": "Our flat is --- the second floor of the building.",
      "options": ["at", "on", "in", "upon"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 827,
      "question": "The antonym for 'Belittle' is --",
      "options": ["Disobey", "Forget", "Magnify", "Extol"],
      "answer": "Magnify"
    },
    {
      "id": 828,
      "question": "Intellectual শব্দের বাংলা অর্থ -",
      "options": ["বুদ্ধিমান", "মননশীল", "বুদ্ধিজীবি", "মেধাবী"],
      "answer": "বুদ্ধিমান"
    },
    {
      "id": 829,
      "question": "Identify the correct synonym for the word 'Treacherous' -",
      "options": ["Unfaithful", "Faithful", "Reliable", "Dependable"],
      "answer": "Unfaithful"
    },
    {
      "id": 830,
      "question": "He broke the jug ---- a hundred pieces.",
      "options": ["in", "at", "into", "with"],
      "answer": "into"
    },
    {
      "id": 831,
      "question": "The 'Mona Lisa' is the portrait of a woman with 'entricing' smile.",
      "options": ["Oblivious", "Luminous", "Alluring", "Elusive"],
      "answer": "Alluring"
    },
    {
      "id": 832,
      "question": "The word 'slim' is closest in meaning to",
      "options": ["Graceful", "Weak", "Soft", "Slender", "Plump"],
      "answer": "Slender"
    },
    {
      "id": 833,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Franchise' is -",
      "options": ["Suffrage", "French", "Utility", "Socialise", "Feverish"],
      "answer": "Suffrage"
    },
    {
      "id": 834,
      "question": "'Value judgement' means -",
      "options": [
        "Valuable judgement",
        "Judgement about price",
        "Famous judgement",
        "Judgement based on personal views"
      ],
      "answer": "Judgement based on personal views"
    },
    {
      "id": 835,
      "question": "If people can't hear you, do you shout ---- them ?",
      "options": ["at", "to", "for", "down"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 836,
      "question": "I am inclined --- stick --- it.",
      "options": ["to / to", "to / for", "for / against", "at / to"],
      "answer": "to / to"
    },
    {
      "id": 837,
      "question": "Crafty men 'Condemn' studies,simple men admire them and wise men use them.",
      "options": ["Denounce", "Laud", "Compliment", "Acclaim"],
      "answer": "Denounce"
    },
    {
      "id": 838,
      "question": "The synonyms of 'Identical' is -",
      "options": [
        "Familiar",
        "Recognisable",
        "Exactly the same",
        "Almost similar"
      ],
      "answer": "Exactly the same"
    },
    {
      "id": 839,
      "question": "Someone who designs house is -",
      "options": ["A designer", "An architect", "A builder", "A plumber"],
      "answer": "An architect"
    },
    {
      "id": 840,
      "question": "An association of sports teams is called a -",
      "options": ["Group", "School", "League", "Game"],
      "answer": "League"
    },
    {
      "id": 841,
      "question": "The word 'Inept' means the same as -",
      "options": ["Unlucky", "Careless", "Disorganized", "Incompetent"],
      "answer": "Incompetent"
    },
    {
      "id": 842,
      "question": "The situation has come to a head' -এর অর্থ -",
      "options": [
        "পরিস্থিতির উন্নতি ঘটেছে",
        "পরিস্থিতির অবনতি ঘটেছে",
        "পরিস্থিতির চরম অবস্থায় পৌঁছেছে",
        "পরিস্থিতি উল্লেখযোগ্য হারে ভালো অবস্থায় এসে দাঁড়িয়েছে"
      ],
      "answer": "পরিস্থিতির চরম অবস্থায় পৌঁছেছে"
    },
    {
      "id": 843,
      "question": "Bullock শব্দের অর্থ",
      "options": ["মহিষ", "খচ্চর", "বৃষ", "ময়ূর"],
      "answer": "বৃষ"
    },
    {
      "id": 844,
      "question": "The synonym for, 'brazen' -",
      "options": ["Shameless", "Quick", "Modest", "Pleasant"],
      "answer": "Shameless"
    },
    {
      "id": 845,
      "question": "A song embodying religious and sacred emotions ---",
      "options": ["Lyric", "Ode", "Hymn", "Ballad"],
      "answer": "Hymn"
    },
    {
      "id": 846,
      "question": "'Razzmatazz' means -",
      "options": [
        "A musical activity",
        "A well-planned program",
        "A noisy activity",
        "A musical instrument"
      ],
      "answer": "A noisy activity"
    },
    {
      "id": 847,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Disappear' is -",
      "options": ["Appear", "Emerge", "Disappoint", "Evaporate"],
      "answer": "Evaporate"
    },
    {
      "id": 848,
      "question": "Which is the synonym of the word ' Unerring' ?",
      "options": ["Infallible", "Ultimate", "Incorrect", "Nervous"],
      "answer": "Infallible"
    },
    {
      "id": 849,
      "question": "BIOSTEROUS is most nearly similar in meaning to",
      "options": ["Conflicting", "Noisy", "Grateful", "Adolescent"],
      "answer": "Noisy"
    },
    {
      "id": 850,
      "question": "The parents should have authority --- their sons and daughters.",
      "options": ["on", "over", "of", "to"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 851,
      "question": "The word ‘Panegyric’ means",
      "options": ["Criticism", "Curse", "Elaborate praise", "High sound"],
      "answer": "Elaborate praise"
    },
    {
      "id": 852,
      "question": "A delusion is -",
      "options": [
        "A dream",
        "Misbelief (illusion)",
        "Stone(rock)",
        "Down-pour"
      ],
      "answer": "Misbelief (illusion)"
    },
    {
      "id": 853,
      "question": "Which one is similar to 'Synopsis' ?",
      "options": ["Brief", "Short note", "Summary", "Resume"],
      "answer": "Summary"
    },
    {
      "id": 854,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'Banish' is -",
      "options": ["To go away", "To move", "To visit", "To exile"],
      "answer": "To exile"
    },
    {
      "id": 855,
      "question": "A myth is -",
      "options": [
        "An adventurous story",
        "A detective story",
        "A mysterious story",
        "A legend"
      ],
      "answer": "A legend"
    },
    {
      "id": 856,
      "question": "He has deprived --- his paternal property.",
      "options": ["from", "of", "with", "in"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 857,
      "question": "The cow feeds ---- grass.",
      "options": ["on", "in", "of", "by"],
      "answer": "on"
    },
    {
      "id": 858,
      "question": "SUMPTUOUS is the most nearly similar in meaning to -",
      "options": ["Fancy", "Meagre", "Lavish", "Swampy"],
      "answer": "Lavish"
    },
    {
      "id": 859,
      "question": "Choose the correct word to fill in the blank, Keep watch on my bag lest the thief --- steal it.",
      "options": ["might not", "should", "should not", "cannot"],
      "answer": "should"
    },
    {
      "id": 860,
      "question": "The expression 'Lingua franca' means -",
      "options": [
        "The common language",
        "The first language",
        "International language",
        "The French language"
      ],
      "answer": "The common language"
    },
    {
      "id": 861,
      "question": "A friend ---- need is a friend indeed .",
      "options": ["to", "for", "in", "at"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 862,
      "question": "Choose the correct antonym of 'Celebrity' ?",
      "options": ["Personality", "Festivity", "Nonentity", "Community"],
      "answer": "Nonentity"
    },
    {
      "id": 863,
      "question": "Cristopher Marlowe was a contemporary --- Shskespeare.",
      "options": ["to", "of", "with", "on"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 864,
      "question": "He ran fast lest he --- miss the train.",
      "options": ["can", "should", "may", "might"],
      "answer": "should"
    },
    {
      "id": 865,
      "question": "The synonyms of 'Noble' is -",
      "options": [
        "Courteous",
        "Big",
        "Virtuous",
        "Of great quality and character"
      ],
      "answer": "Of great quality and character"
    },
    {
      "id": 866,
      "question": "Perfunctory শব্দটির সঠিক প্রতিশব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Thorough", "Lively", "Impossible", "Listless"],
      "answer": "Listless"
    },
    {
      "id": 867,
      "question": "The antonym of 'Atheist' is -",
      "options": ["Agnostic", "Idealist", "Believer", "Non-believer"],
      "answer": "Believer"
    },
    {
      "id": 868,
      "question": "He relieved me --- anxiety.",
      "options": ["in", "from", "with", "to"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 869,
      "question": "He sat there brooding --- whether life was worth living.",
      "options": ["over", "about", "of", "upon"],
      "answer": "over"
    },
    {
      "id": 870,
      "question": "It 's impolite to break --- when some one else is talking.",
      "options": ["in", "on", "into", "off"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 871,
      "question": "'Antithesis' is the antonym of -",
      "options": ["velocity", "maxim", "similarity", "reaction"],
      "answer": "similarity"
    },
    {
      "id": 872,
      "question": "'Competent' means -",
      "options": ["Competitive", "Communicative", "Strong", "Able"],
      "answer": "Answer not available."
    },
    {
      "id": 873,
      "question": "A specialist in eye diseases is called -",
      "options": [
        "A cardiologist",
        "An opthalmologist",
        "An optician",
        "A neurologist"
      ],
      "answer": "An opthalmologist"
    },
    {
      "id": 874,
      "question": "'Penury' is most nearly opposite to the meaning -",
      "options": [
        "Penance",
        "Pensiveness",
        "Wealth",
        "Impenetrability",
        "Silence"
      ],
      "answer": "Wealth"
    },
    {
      "id": 875,
      "question": "The ship sailed --- of the ice waters --- another sea.",
      "options": ["on , from", "out , into", "of , into", "to , out"],
      "answer": "out , into"
    },
    {
      "id": 876,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Anarchy' ?",
      "options": ["Unrest", "Instability", "Peace", "Lawlessness"],
      "answer": "Peace"
    },
    {
      "id": 877,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Notice' is -",
      "options": ["Club", "Lead", "Imagination", "Concept"],
      "answer": "Concept"
    },
    {
      "id": 878,
      "question": "No one was going to listen to his drivel. Here \"Drivel\" means -",
      "options": [
        "Amusing talk",
        "Monotonous talk",
        "Silky talk",
        "Dishonest talk"
      ],
      "answer": "Silky talk"
    },
    {
      "id": 879,
      "question": "An antonym of 'hungry' is -",
      "options": ["Satiated", "Angry", "Feeling", "Thirsty"],
      "answer": "Satiated"
    },
    {
      "id": 880,
      "question": "Sliloquey means ---",
      "options": [
        "To memorise",
        "Talking to oneself",
        "Action of speech",
        "Rehearsal of a play"
      ],
      "answer": "Talking to oneself"
    },
    {
      "id": 881,
      "question": "What is the synonym of the word 'sticky' ?",
      "options": ["Adhesive", "Glutinous", "Irony", "Silky"],
      "answer": "Adhesive"
    },
    {
      "id": 882,
      "question": "He is bent ---- going to the meeting. বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানের সঠিক শব্দ বসবে -",
      "options": ["upon", "on", "in", "with"],
      "answer": "upon"
    },
    {
      "id": 883,
      "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'Nascent'?",
      "options": ["Trail", "Nasal", "Odorous", "Beginning"],
      "answer": "Beginning"
    },
    {
      "id": 884,
      "question": "'Modus Operandi' means -",
      "options": [
        "Failed operation",
        "Method of operation",
        "Opera song",
        "Suitable object"
      ],
      "answer": "Method of operation"
    },
    {
      "id": 885,
      "question": "Select the right word/words: I do not believe ------ his honesty.",
      "options": ["in", "at", "with", "to"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 886,
      "question": "'The synonym for 'Obdurate'",
      "options": [
        "Decitful (প্রবঞ্চনাপূর্ণ)",
        "Stubborn(অবাধ্য,জেদী)",
        "Sly (গোপন)",
        "Swindler(প্রতারক)"
      ],
      "answer": "Stubborn(অবাধ্য,জেদী)"
    },
    {
      "id": 887,
      "question": "He compared the heart --- a pump.",
      "options": ["to", "with", "at", "by"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 888,
      "question": "'Cursory' is the similar of -",
      "options": ["Hand written", "Angry", "Hasty", "Vulgar"],
      "answer": "Hasty"
    },
    {
      "id": 889,
      "question": "The word 'Expunge' means",
      "options": ["Rationalize", "Purge", "Inhale", "Eradicate"],
      "answer": "Eradicate"
    },
    {
      "id": 890,
      "question": "It is 'imperative' that they arrive on time for the lecture.",
      "options": ["Necessary", "Suggested", "Hoped", "Intended"],
      "answer": "Necessary"
    },
    {
      "id": 891,
      "question": "The synonym for 'Skepticism' is -",
      "options": [
        "Doubt",
        "Skating people",
        "Symptoms",
        "Diminutive",
        "Wonderful"
      ],
      "answer": "Doubt"
    },
    {
      "id": 892,
      "question": "'Hedge' means -",
      "options": ["Curse", "Injure", "Evade", "Harm"],
      "answer": "Evade"
    },
    {
      "id": 893,
      "question": "Karim had his car --- by a mechanic yesterday.",
      "options": [
        "to repair",
        "be repaired",
        "repairing",
        "repaired",
        "was repaired"
      ],
      "answer": "was repaired"
    },
    {
      "id": 894,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Genesis' is --",
      "options": ["Introduction", "Preface", "Beginning", "Foreword"],
      "answer": "Beginning"
    },
    {
      "id": 895,
      "question": "The expression 'to see red' means ---",
      "options": [
        "To become very angry",
        "To draw blood",
        "To be enthusiastic",
        "To be lethargic"
      ],
      "answer": "To become very angry"
    },
    {
      "id": 896,
      "question": "It is high time we ---- the place.",
      "options": ["leave", "have left", "are leaving", "left"],
      "answer": "left"
    },
    {
      "id": 897,
      "question": "Which of the flowing is not the appropriate bangla",
      "options": [
        "Exorcise:প্রমোদ ভ্রমণ",
        "Emigrate:দেশত্যাগ করা",
        "Envious:ঈরষা",
        "Exhort:উপদেশ দারা উৎসাহিত করা"
      ],
      "answer": "Exorcise:প্রমোদ ভ্রমণ"
    },
    {
      "id": 898,
      "question": "A physician is a -",
      "options": [
        "Physicist",
        "Physique",
        "A medical practitioner",
        "A physical trainer"
      ],
      "answer": "A medical practitioner"
    },
    {
      "id": 899,
      "question": "The antonym of INFRINGE is -",
      "options": ["Transgress", "Purloin", "Invaded", "Intrude"],
      "answer": "Transgress"
    },
    {
      "id": 900,
      "question": "Choose the word opposite in meaning to the given word: LIABILITY",
      "options": ["Treasure", "Debt", "Assets", "Property"],
      "answer": "Assets"
    },
    {
      "id": 901,
      "question": "I can't help but laugh. The correct form is ---?",
      "options": [
        "I can only laugh",
        "I can help myself to laugh",
        "I can not help laughing",
        "All of them"
      ],
      "answer": "I can not help laughing"
    },
    {
      "id": 902,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Craft' is -",
      "options": ["Mural", "Skill", "Fabric", "Sketch"],
      "answer": "Skill"
    },
    {
      "id": 903,
      "question": "He did it ----- his own accord.",
      "options": ["of", "at", "by", "on"],
      "answer": "of"
    },
    {
      "id": 904,
      "question": "Ensure শব্দটির অর্থ কোনটি?",
      "options": ["Make progress", "Encourage", "Effect", "Make certain"],
      "answer": "Make certain"
    },
    {
      "id": 905,
      "question": "To replicate means -",
      "options": [
        "To understand",
        "To enunciate",
        "To be serious",
        "To motivate",
        "To copy"
      ],
      "answer": "To copy"
    },
    {
      "id": 906,
      "question": "Which of the following pair contain correct synonym?",
      "options": [
        "Influence : Lead",
        "Informed : Instructive",
        "Injure : Hurt",
        "Inspection : Observer"
      ],
      "answer": "Injure : Hurt"
    },
    {
      "id": 907,
      "question": "Choose the opposite in meaning of the word 'Arrogant'",
      "options": ["Insolent", "Proud", "Rude", "Meek"],
      "answer": "Meek"
    },
    {
      "id": 908,
      "question": "'Hurry up! we have to go ---- five minutes'",
      "options": ["in", "on", "by", "for"],
      "answer": "in"
    },
    {
      "id": 909,
      "question": "Identify the correct synonym for the word 'Instigate'.",
      "options": ["Investigate", "Incite", "Instil", "Intoxicate"],
      "answer": "Incite"
    },
    {
      "id": 910,
      "question": "The word 'dilly dally' means ---",
      "options": ["To dilute", "Wait impatiently", "Repeat", "Waste time"],
      "answer": "Waste time"
    },
    {
      "id": 911,
      "question": "'The word 'Benevolent' means -",
      "options": ["Kind", "Unkind", "Cruel", "Honest"],
      "answer": "Kind"
    },
    {
      "id": 912,
      "question": "What is the antonym of 'Courage' ?",
      "options": ["Forceful", "Strength", "Cowardice", "Daring"],
      "answer": "Cowardice"
    },
    {
      "id": 913,
      "question": "I wish I (sing).What is the correct form of the verb in the bracket?",
      "options": ["Sang", "Am singing", "Have sung", "Had sung"],
      "answer": "Sang"
    },
    {
      "id": 914,
      "question": "Antonym of \"Shift\"",
      "options": ["Anchor", "Fix", "Attach", "Bind"],
      "answer": "Attach"
    },
    {
      "id": 915,
      "question": "The synonyms of 'Pungent' is -",
      "options": ["Tide", "Rain", "Overpowering", "Bland", "Good"],
      "answer": "Overpowering"
    },
    {
      "id": 916,
      "question": "The students have submitted the report today which they --- to bring yesterday.",
      "options": [
        "was supposed",
        "were supposed",
        "was supposed",
        "were supposed",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "None of these"
    },
    {
      "id": 917,
      "question": "Single word for 'the man who is not married' is -",
      "options": ["Spinster", "Virgin", "Bachelor", "Non-married"],
      "answer": "Bachelor"
    },
    {
      "id": 918,
      "question": "I regret to say that his disease is ----",
      "options": ["Curable", "Incurable", "Cired", "Incured"],
      "answer": "Incurable"
    },
    {
      "id": 919,
      "question": "The synonym of 'Astonishing' -",
      "options": ["Unquestionable", "Surprising", "Cunning", "Assured"],
      "answer": "Surprising"
    },
    {
      "id": 920,
      "question": "Wisdom means",
      "options": ["Foolishness", "Trick", "Intelligence", "Prudence"],
      "answer": "Prudence"
    },
    {
      "id": 921,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Fickle' ?",
      "options": ["Constant", "Stable", "Unstable", "Trustworthy"],
      "answer": "Unstable"
    },
    {
      "id": 922,
      "question": "\"A laconic speech\" is -",
      "options": [
        "A piece of advice",
        "An angry speech",
        "A sermon",
        "A concise speech"
      ],
      "answer": "A concise speech"
    },
    {
      "id": 923,
      "question": "Choose the word that is the opposite of 'relaxed' ?",
      "options": ["Tense", "Easy going", "Happy", "Contented"],
      "answer": "Tense"
    },
    {
      "id": 924,
      "question": "What is the collective noun for a group of young partridges?",
      "options": ["Gaggle", "Covey", "Flock", "School"],
      "answer": "Covey"
    },
    {
      "id": 925,
      "question": "'The word 'Sanction' means -",
      "options": ["Verify", "Plan", "Prohibit", "Authorization"],
      "answer": "Authorization"
    },
    {
      "id": 926,
      "question": "He is not for changing things; he is for preserving the -",
      "options": ["Vice versa", "Bona fide", "Ex officio", "Status quo"],
      "answer": "Status quo"
    },
    {
      "id": 927,
      "question": "Synonym of 'Vanity' is -",
      "options": [
        "Over-consciousness",
        "Pride",
        "Self-confidence",
        "Frivolousness"
      ],
      "answer": "Pride"
    },
    {
      "id": 928,
      "question": "The synonym of the word 'Morose' is -",
      "options": ["Vindictive", "Adventurous", "Depressed", "Cheerful"],
      "answer": "Depressed"
    },
    {
      "id": 929,
      "question": "I don't feel ---- Rahman. All his problems are entirely his creation.",
      "options": ["sorry for", "sorry at", "sorry about", "sorry upon"],
      "answer": "sorry for"
    },
    {
      "id": 930,
      "question": "Choose the correct word for the gap in the sentence. My father insists on ---- quality materials for the construction of our new house.",
      "options": ["use", "to use", "the use", "using"],
      "answer": "using"
    },
    {
      "id": 931,
      "question": "Choose the one that best expresses the meaning of the given word: Sporadic",
      "options": ["Consistent", "Uniform", "Frequent", "Scattered"],
      "answer": "Scattered"
    },
    {
      "id": 932,
      "question": "The synonyms of 'Identical' is -",
      "options": ["Familiar", "Recognisable", "Same", "Close"],
      "answer": "Same"
    },
    {
      "id": 933,
      "question": "\"We discussed the hazardous journey ahead of us.\"Here hazardous means:",
      "options": ["Enjoyable", "Approaching", "Dangerous", "Comfortable"],
      "answer": "Dangerous"
    },
    {
      "id": 934,
      "question": "He dropped his voice ---- a whisper.",
      "options": ["in", "to", "from", "at"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 935,
      "question": "Which is the antonym of 'Transparent' ?",
      "options": ["Opaque", "Clear", "Honest", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "Opaque"
    },
    {
      "id": 936,
      "question": "The word 'Somnambulist means",
      "options": [
        "A sleep-worker",
        "A day dreamer",
        "A night dreamer",
        "An optimist"
      ],
      "answer": "A sleep-worker"
    },
    {
      "id": 937,
      "question": "The customer gets what he pays -----?",
      "options": ["off", "at", "for", "from"],
      "answer": "from"
    },
    {
      "id": 938,
      "question": "Choose the word that is opposite to the word 'consolidation'.",
      "options": [
        "Instigation",
        "Fragmentation",
        "Restriction",
        "Opposition",
        "Provocation"
      ],
      "answer": "Fragmentation"
    },
    {
      "id": 939,
      "question": "The synonym for 'Meticulous' is -",
      "options": [
        "Delightful",
        "Careful and exact",
        "Having strength of mind",
        "Careless"
      ],
      "answer": "Careful and exact"
    },
    {
      "id": 940,
      "question": "Which of the following is correct ?",
      "options": [
        "I was stuck in traffic for two hours",
        "I was stuck up in traffic for two hours",
        "I had stuck up in traffic for two hours",
        "I had stuck in traffic for two hours"
      ],
      "answer": "I was stuck in traffic for two hours"
    },
    {
      "id": 941,
      "question": "Desolate শব্দটির সঠিক antonym কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Populous", "Isolated", "Abandoned", "Disfigured"],
      "answer": "Populous"
    },
    {
      "id": 942,
      "question": "I wish I ---- a rich man.",
      "options": ["shall be", "were", "am", "to be"],
      "answer": "were"
    },
    {
      "id": 943,
      "question": "A suitable antonym for 'Meticulous' is -",
      "options": ["Painstaking", "Careless", "Thorough", "Mindful"],
      "answer": "Careless"
    },
    {
      "id": 944,
      "question": "Would you mind ---- a folk song.",
      "options": ["for", "singing", "sing", "in"],
      "answer": "singing"
    },
    {
      "id": 945,
      "question": "I was disappointed --- the grades I received on my last essay.",
      "options": ["by", "to", "with/in", "at"],
      "answer": "at"
    },
    {
      "id": 946,
      "question": "I depended ---- his word . বাক্যের শূণ্যস্থানে সঠিক শব্দ বসবে --?",
      "options": ["on", "upon", "in", "at"],
      "answer": "upon"
    },
    {
      "id": 947,
      "question": "My sister brings colour and happiness ---- my life.",
      "options": ["to", "with", "in", "on"],
      "answer": "to"
    },
    {
      "id": 948,
      "question": "What is the antonym of the word 'Belittle'",
      "options": ["Worthless", "Dull", "Glorify", "Useless"],
      "answer": "Glorify"
    },
    {
      "id": 949,
      "question": "My wife reminded me ----",
      "options": [
        "of my appointment",
        "to go my appointment",
        "to my appointment",
        "my appointment"
      ],
      "answer": "of my appointment"
    },
    {
      "id": 950,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Adjourn'?",
      "options": ["To run", "To stop", "To cry", "To laugh"],
      "answer": "To stop"
    },
    {
      "id": 951,
      "question": "'Multiple' means -",
      "options": ["Compound", "Few", "Little", "Great", "Many"],
      "answer": "Many"
    },
    {
      "id": 952,
      "question": "Synonyms's of Compensation",
      "options": ["Satisfaction", "Admission", "Compromise", "Reward"],
      "answer": "Reward"
    },
    {
      "id": 953,
      "question": "Select the word closest in meaning to the word-পর্যাপ্ত",
      "options": ["Lack", "Unwanted", "Sharper", "Adequate"],
      "answer": "Adequate"
    },
    {
      "id": 954,
      "question": "A person who hates the company of others is -",
      "options": ["Antisocial", "Unsociable", "Unknown", "Gregarious"],
      "answer": "Unsociable"
    },
    {
      "id": 955,
      "question": "Which is the synonym of 'Ruthless' ?",
      "options": ["Merciless", "Tender", "Disproved", "Leave"],
      "answer": "Merciless"
    },
    {
      "id": 956,
      "question": "Which sentence is correct?",
      "options": [
        "He is not on the committee",
        "He is not in the committee",
        "He is not with the committee",
        "He is not at the committee"
      ],
      "answer": "He is not on the committee"
    },
    {
      "id": 957,
      "question": "Many prefer donating money --- distributing clothes.",
      "options": ["Than", "But", "To", "Without"],
      "answer": "To"
    },
    {
      "id": 958,
      "question": "What is the opposite of 'Cordial'",
      "options": ["Gentle", "Heartly", "Ungrateful", "Reserved"],
      "answer": "Reserved"
    },
    {
      "id": 959,
      "question": "'The Himalayas is --- the north of India'. Put appropriate preposition in the blank.",
      "options": ["In", "On", "Into", "To"],
      "answer": "To"
    },
    {
      "id": 960,
      "question": "'benevolent' means -",
      "options": [
        "Compassionate",
        "Compromifull",
        "Honoraarrium",
        "Disgraceful"
      ],
      "answer": "Compassionate"
    },
    {
      "id": 961,
      "question": "'Corpus' means",
      "options": [
        "A dead body",
        "A collection of written texts",
        "Red or white cells in blood",
        "One of the technical branches of an army"
      ],
      "answer": "A collection of written texts"
    },
    {
      "id": 962,
      "question": "Effort শব্দটির synonym হচ্ছে -",
      "options": ["Assurance", "Attempt", "Erect", "Exclude"],
      "answer": "Attempt"
    },
    {
      "id": 963,
      "question": "'Alert' means",
      "options": ["Energetic", "Intelligent", "Observant", "Watchful"],
      "answer": "Watchful"
    },
    {
      "id": 964,
      "question": "Antonym of 'Crux'",
      "options": ["Affliction", "Spark", "Events", "Trivial point"],
      "answer": "Trivial point"
    },
    {
      "id": 965,
      "question": "Please ---- the necessity of arriving early.",
      "options": [
        "Emphasise about",
        "Emphasise to",
        "Emphasise of",
        "Emphasise"
      ],
      "answer": "Emphasise"
    },
    {
      "id": 966,
      "question": "'Stability' is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "Disparity",
        "Inconsistency",
        "Carelessness",
        "Weariness",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Inconsistency"
    },
    {
      "id": 967,
      "question": "N.B. অর্থ কি ?",
      "options": ["Note Before", "Nota Bene", "Note By", "Note Best"],
      "answer": "Nota Bene"
    },
    {
      "id": 968,
      "question": "'Sagacity' is opposite to -",
      "options": [
        "Incredulity",
        "Belligerence",
        "Stupidity",
        "Tolerance",
        "Independence"
      ],
      "answer": "Stupidity"
    },
    {
      "id": 969,
      "question": "'She works at a snail's pace' means",
      "options": [
        "She works steadily",
        "She works slowly",
        "She works smoothly",
        "She works thoughtfully"
      ],
      "answer": "She works slowly"
    },
    {
      "id": 970,
      "question": "Which one is connected to complain?",
      "options": ["Dodge", "Hodge", "Lodged", "Grudge"],
      "answer": "Lodged"
    },
    {
      "id": 971,
      "question": "I wish I ---- wonderful man.",
      "options": ["Was", "Were", "Would be", "Am"],
      "answer": "Were"
    },
    {
      "id": 972,
      "question": "Fill in the blank with appropriate word. She sent me that --- Christmas.",
      "options": ["By", "To", "In", "For"],
      "answer": "For"
    },
    {
      "id": 973,
      "question": "Which do you think is the nearest in meaning to “proviso”:",
      "options": ["Sanction", "Substitute", "Stipulation", "Directive"],
      "answer": "Stipulation"
    },
    {
      "id": 974,
      "question": "What is the synonym of 'Sychophant' ?",
      "options": ["Dignified person", "Flatterer", "Phoney", "Dishonour"],
      "answer": "Flatterer"
    },
    {
      "id": 975,
      "question": "They were charged ---- receiving stolen books.",
      "options": ["By", "With", "From", "On"],
      "answer": "With"
    },
    {
      "id": 976,
      "question": "Find the antonym of the word : Awful",
      "options": ["Clumsy", "Difficult", "Graceful", "Skillful", "Fantastic"],
      "answer": "Fantastic"
    },
    {
      "id": 977,
      "question": "'Flamboyant' is opposite to -",
      "options": ["Lateral", "Dull", "Maverick", "Antique", "Loud"],
      "answer": "Dull"
    },
    {
      "id": 978,
      "question": "Find out the correct sentence of the following:",
      "options": [
        "He availed with the opportunity",
        "He was availed with the opportunity",
        "He was availed of the opportunity",
        "He was availed himself of the opportunity"
      ],
      "answer": "He was availed himself of the opportunity"
    },
    {
      "id": 979,
      "question": "A dwarfed ornamental tree or shrub grown in a tray or shallow pot-",
      "options": [
        "Topiary",
        "Fabrication",
        "Gardening",
        "Bonsai",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "answer": "Bonsai"
    },
    {
      "id": 980,
      "question": "Select the word that is the most closely opposite in meaning to the capitalized word: DELETERIOUS",
      "options": ["Toxic", "Spurious", "Harmless", "Lethal"],
      "answer": "Harmless"
    },
    {
      "id": 981,
      "question": "Hardly had the train stopped ----",
      "options": [
        "Before we got down",
        "As we got down",
        "Than we got down",
        "When we got down"
      ],
      "answer": "Before we got down"
    },
    {
      "id": 982,
      "question": "We dispensed ---- his services.",
      "options": ["For", "With", "Of", "In"],
      "answer": "With"
    },
    {
      "id": 983,
      "question": "'Righteous' means-",
      "options": ["Just", "Sinful", "Amoral", "Rigid"],
      "answer": "Just"
    },
    {
      "id": 984,
      "question": "Choose the meaning of 'White Elephant':",
      "options": [
        "An elephant of white colour",
        "Very costly or troublesome",
        "Precious",
        "Very big"
      ],
      "answer": "Very costly or troublesome"
    },
    {
      "id": 985,
      "question": "'Clandestine' শব্দটির বিপরীত অর্থবোধক শব্দ কোনটি ?",
      "options": ["Overt", "Coverted", "Covertd", "Intractable"],
      "answer": "Overt"
    },
    {
      "id": 986,
      "question": "As they waited Rahim argued against war -",
      "options": [
        "While his brother discusses the effects of pollution",
        "While his brother discusseed the effects of pollution",
        "While his brother was discussing the effects of pollution",
        "While his brother had discussed the effects of pollution"
      ],
      "answer": "While his brother was discussing the effects of pollution"
    },
    {
      "id": 987,
      "question": "The antonym of the word 'Benign' is -",
      "options": ["Tenfold", "Peaceful", "Blessed", "Malignant"],
      "answer": "Malignant"
    }
  ]
}
